<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>12 Minute Sun-Dried Tomato Chicken Pasta Toss</name>
        <category>Pasta</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Prepare the pasta and chicken mixture simultaneously.

Prepare pasta according to directions of pkg.

Heat 2 Tbsp. of tomato olive oil from jar in skillet on medium heat. Add crushed garlic, dry basil, dry oregano, garlic powder and salt to bite size pieces of chicken . Sate" approx. 5 to 7 minutes, until chicken is no longer pink in color.

Drain tomatoes from jar and add to chicken skillet mixture and stir. Reduce heat and saute' for 3 minutes.

Toss chicken-tomato mixture with prepared psta. Add Parmesan cheese to each serving.</directions>
        <ingredients>4 skinless, boneless chicken breast, cut into bite size pieces
1 12 oz. pkg. or plain rotini pasta (or similar spiral pasta)
1 cup sun-dried tomatoes (julienne cut or sliced)
2 Tbsp. oil from sun-dried tomatoes
1 tsp. crushed garlic
1 tsp. dry basil
1 tsp. dried oregano
1 tsp. garlic powder
1 tsp. salt
Parmesan Cheese
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Aioli</name>
        <category>Sauce</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>1. In a food processor fitted with a steel blade, mince the garlic. Add the egg and process until completely mixed. With the motor running, slowly pour in 1/4 cup of the olive oil. Stop the machine and add the lemon juice. Then, with the motor running, slowly add the remaining 1/2 cup olive oil and process until the mixture is thickened and the oil is emulsified. Add salt and pepper to taste.

2. Refrigerate for at least 30 minutes and up to 8 hours before serving to allow the raw garlic flavor to mellow a little.Helpful Hints
Be sure to keep the aioli refrigerated in warm weather. It's a good idea to make it early in the day, then chill well. This gives the raw garlic a chance to mellow and allows you to serve a chilled dip, which spoils less quickly.</directions>
        <ingredients>4 garlic cloves
1 egg
3/4 cup extra-virgin olive oil
juice of 1/2 lemon
salt and black pepper
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Alaska Bob's Fish Tacos</name>
        <category>Fish</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>In a glass bowl, combine marinade ingredients. Slice fish into half inch wide strips, approximately 2 inches long. Add fish strips to marinade and mix well. Marinade fish for at least one hour. Preheat oven to 350 degrees. Place fish strips onto a lightly oiled cookie sheet. Cook fish strips for approximately 8 minutes turning once.

To prepare fish Tacos, warm corn tortillas in the oven. Place a warmed tortilla flat onto a plate. Spread a thin layer of sour cream over the tortilla. Place one or two fish strips, some shredded cabbage, and garnish with taco sauce or ranch dressing. Fold tortilla in half and enjoy!</directions>
        <ingredients>Fish Taco Marinade
1T Soy Sauce
1/2 tsp cumin
3 tsp olive oil
1/4 lime - juice from

Fish Taco Ingredients
1lb halibut or snapper fillet
2 cups shredded cabbage
Sour Cream
Salsa
Ranch dressing
8 corn tortillas</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>2</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Almond and Orange Zest Biscotti</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat the oven to 350F (175C). Whisk the flour, baking powder, and salt together.

Select a mixing bowl that is large enough to hold all the ingredients and still provide enough room to fold them together without making a mess.

Break two large eggs into the large mixing bowl and add the sugar. Whisk to combine.

Continue whisking the sugar and eggs until the color has lightened to a pale yellow. I like using a spare piece of mesh cabinet liner to keep the bowl from shifting while I'm whisking.

Add the vanilla extract, almond extract, and slivered almonds to the egg and sugar mixture. Using a spatula, stir once or twice to combine.
Working in batches, pour enough of the flour mixture to cover the surface of the egg mixture. Use a spatula and fold in the flour using as few strokes as possible. Add more flour and fold until all the flour has been integrated. Folding is performed by using a spatula to scoop from either the side or the middle of the mixture and lifting and folding (basically movign the spatula laterally and then flipping it over to drop the mixture) onto another part of the mixture. Rotate the bowl each fold.

The key is not to stir or mix the flour with the liquid too much. Gently folding helps prevents the formation of too much elastic gluten. The presence of too much gluten will defeat the delicate and crisp texture we are trying to achieve and result in a possibly chewy product.

Split the batter in half and place the two rough balls onto a non-stick baking sheet (such as a silicone baking mat or parchment paper set in a half sheet pan). With your hands, form the batter into two loaves of approximately 10-in. (25 cm) by 2 in. (5 cm) each. Wetting your hands just a bit may help with molding the loaves since the batter will be fairly sticky.

Bake the loaves at 350F (175C) for 40 minutes (rotating the pan once after twenty minutes). The loaves should have just started to crack. (Don't wait for big cracks or you might overcook the biscotti.)

Remove the loaves from the pan and place them on a wire rack to cool for at least ten minutes. This cooling step is extremely important to your non-dominant hand as it will be holding the loaf while you cut it in the next step.

After some cooling, move a loaf to a cutting board and cut diagonally into 3/8-in. (1 cm) thick pieces. Do the same to the other loaf. The interior of each biscotto should still be just a little moist (while the exterior is nice and hard). The crust of the loaf will probably be quite hard, so use a large serrated knife such as a bread knife for this job.

Place the biscotti with a cut side facing up on a half sheet pan and bake for 8 minutes. Remove the pan and flip all the biscotti over so the other cut side is now facing up. Bake for another 7 minutes. Set all the pieces on a wire rack to cool making sure that none of the biscotti are touching each other. If the biscotti are placed too close together, they could get a little soft or soggy as they cool.

Once the biscotti have fully cooled, they can be consumed as is, or chocolate dipped. To chocolate dip, simply break up the chocolate of your choice (dark chocolate is Tina's favorite) and place in a large metal mixing bowl. I find it easier to dip biscotti in large quantities of chocolate, so I usually make two batches of biscotti (4 loaves), and melt about 250 g (a bit more than 1/2 pound) chocolate. For one batch, 125 g (about 1/4 pound) chocolate should be enough. Using a flat bottomed mixing bowl also makes it easier to dip (otherwise you may need to transfer the chocolate to another container after melting to dip the biscotti).

Place the mixing bowl with the chocolate over a saucepan containing about an inch of water (but not so much that the mixing bowl will actually make contact with the water). Bring the water to a boil and then reduce the heat to a simmer. Once the chocolate begins to melt, you can turn off the heat and let the residual heat and steam continue to heat the bowl and melt the chocolate.

Stir occassionally to check when the chocolate has completely melted. Once the chocolate has melted, you can leave the mixing bowl over the hot water to keep the chocolate warm and melted as you dip the biscotti.

Dip each biscotto in the chocolate by inserting the flat bottom into the chocolate. Use a spatula to remove any excess chocolate and then lay the biscotto (chocolate side down) on a silicone mat or sheet of parchment paper. Repeat until all the biscotti have been dipped. The biscotti can then be left to cool on its own or placed in the refrigerator.

The biscotti tastes best during the first few days, but will keep for up to a month in a sealed air-tight container</directions>
        <ingredients>1 cup (200 g) sugar 
2 large eggs
3/4 cup (80 g) slivered almonds 
2 tablespoons minced orange zest (about half an orange's zest)
1 teaspoon baking powder (fresh, consider doubling)
1/4 teaspoon salt
2 cups (250 g) flour
1/2 teaspoon vanilla extract
1/4 teaspoon almond extract</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Alsatian-style Apple Pie</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>For crust: 
Blend flour, sugar, and salt in processor. Add butter and shortening; cut in using on/off turns until mixture resembles coarse meal. Blend in enough ice water using on/off turns until dough begins to form clumps. 
Gather dough into ball; flatten into disk. Wrap in plastic and refrigerate 1 hour.

For filling: 
Whisk eggs and 1/2 cup sugar in large bowl to blend. Whisk in cream, milk, kirsch, and spices. Cook 2 tablespoons butter in heavy large skillet over medium-high heat until butter begins to brown, about 2 minutes. Whisk into cream mixture. Set custard aside.

Melt remaining 2 tablespoons butter in same skillet over medium heat. 
Add apples and remaining 1/4 cup sugar; saute until apples begin to soften, about 8 minutes. Increase heat to medium-high; saute until apples are tender and golden brown, about 7 minutes longer. Cool.

Roll out dough on lightly floured surface to 12 1/2-inch round. Transfer to 9-inch-diameter pie dish. Fold dough edges under and crimp decoratively. Pierce crust all over with fork. Freeze 20 minutes.

Preheat oven to 400F. Line crust with foil. Fill with dried beans or pie weights. Bake 10 minutes. Remove foil and beans. Bake until crust is golden, about 15 minutes longer. Cool slightly. Reduce oven temperature 
to 350F. Arrange apple mixture in pie shell. Pour custard over. Bake until knife inserted into center comes out clean, covering crust with foil if browning too quickly, about 40 minutes. Transfer pie to rack and cool slightly. Serve wa</directions>
        <ingredients>Crust
1 1/3 cups all purpose flour
2 tablespoons sugar
1/2 teaspoon salt
6 tablespoons chilled unsalted butter, cut into 1/2-inch pieces
2 tablespoons chilled solid vegetable shortening, cut into 1/2-inch 
pieces
3 tablespoons (about) ice water

Filling
3 large eggs
3/4 cup sugar
1/2 cup whipping cream
1/2 cup whole milk
1 teaspoon kirsch (clear cherry brandy) 
1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon
Generous pinch of ground nutmeg
4 tablespoons (1/2 stick) unsalted butter

4 medium Golden Delicious apples, peeled, cored, cut into 1/2-inch-thick 
wedges</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Amanda s Banana Split Cheesecake</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix graham cracker crumbs, 1/4 c. sugar and butter. Press on bottom of 13x9 baking pan. Blend cream cheese, remaining sugar, and vanilla in bowl with mixer at med. speed. Add eggs mix until blended. Stir in mashed bananas. Pour into crust. Bake at 350 for 30 min. or until center is almost set. Cool. Refrigerate 3 hrs. or overnight. Top with straberries, sliced banana. Sprinkle with nuts and drizzle with chocolate. Cut into squares to serve.</directions>
        <ingredients>28 squares low fat Honey Maid Honey Grahams, finely crushed (about 2 c. crumbs)
1 C. sugar, divided
1/3 C. butter
3 (8 oz) cream cheese, softened
1 tsp. vanilla
3 eggs
1/2 c. mashed banana
1 C. halved strawberries
1 banana, sliced, tossed with 1 tsp. lemon juice
1 (8 oz) can pinapple chunks, drained
chopped walnuts
chocolate syrup</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Amanda's (Slightly) Famous Chocolate Cake</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F (180 degrees C / gas 4). Beat the sugar and butter until pale and fluffy. Sieve the lour and baking powder into the butter mixture. Add the eggs and mix it all together. Then mix the cocoa powder with 8 tablespoons of warm water, until smooth.

Fold the chocolate paste, almonds, and chocolate pieces into the cake mixture. Pour the mixture into a greased baking tin, spreading it out evenly. Bake for about 18 to 20 minutes.
</directions>
        <ingredients>7 ounces sugar
7 ounces butter
7 ounces self-raising flour,sifted
1 rounded teaspoon baking powder
3 large eggs, preferably free-range
3 rounded tablespoons cocoa powder
8 tablespoons warm water
Handful flaked almonds
3 3/4 ounces cooking chocolate, broken up

Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F (180 degrees C / gas 4). Beat the sugar and butter until pale and fluffy. Sieve the flour and baking powder into the butter mixture. Add the eggs and mix it all together. Then mix the cocoa powder with 8 tablespoons of warm water, until smooth.

Fold the chocolate paste, almonds, and chocolate pieces into the cake mixture. Pour the mixture into a greased baking tin, spreading it out evenly. Bake for about 18 to 20
minutes.

For the chocolate sauce:
3 3/4 ounces cooking chocolate
3 3/4 ounces confectioners sugar
3 3/4 ounces butter
4 tablespoons milk

Meanwhile, melt the chocolate sauce ingredients in a bowl over some lightly simmering water. Stir until blended well.
When the pudding is cooked, remove from the oven and pour over the chocolate sauce while still hot.

Yield: 8 servings
Prep Time: 10 minutes
Cook Time: 30 minutes
Difficulty: Medium
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Ancho Pork Medallions</name>
        <category>Pork</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Cut pork crosswise into 8 equal pieces. Combine chile powder and next ingredients (through allspice) in a small bowl; rub evenly over both sides of pork. Combine jelly and lime juice; set aside.

Heat oil in a large heavy skillet over medium-high heat. Add pork to pan; cook 1 minute on each side. Brush pork with half of jelly mixture; turn and brush with remaining jelly mixture. Cook 1 minute on each side or until desired degree of doneness.

Remove pork from pan; let stand 5 minutes before serving.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 (1lb.) pork tenderloin, thrimmed
3/4 Tsp. ancho chile powder
1/2 Tsp. salt
1/4 Tsp. sugar
1/4 Tsp. ground cumin
1/8 Tsp. ground allspice
2 Tbl. jalapeño pepper jelly
1 Tsp. lime juice
2 Tsp. olive oil</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Andouille with Chickpeas &amp; Tomato </name>
        <category>Legume</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat a frying pan with 2 tablespoons olive oil on high. Stir fry chorizo until nicely brown on both sides.
Stir through chickpeas &amp; paprika and cook for another minute or two.
Taste, season, and stir through tomato and parsley.</directions>
        <ingredients>4-5 Andouille sausages, sliced into coins
2 can chickpeas (400g or 14oz), drained
2 teaspoons smoked paprika, optional
1 box cherry tomatoes, halved
1/2 bunch flat leaf parsley, roughly chopped</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Anise Candy</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>REMOVE AND ADD 1 TABLESPOON OF ANISE OIL.
10 DROPS OF RED FOOD COLORING. 
QUICKLY STIR TO MIX. 
POUR INTO BUTTERED PAN. 
WHEN COOLED BREAK INTO PIECES.</directions>
        <ingredients>BOIL TO CRACK STAGE. 280 DEGREES
2 CUPS OF WHITE SUGAR
1 CUP OF WATER
3/4 CUP OF WHITE CORN SYRUP</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Apple Pie</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat oven to 425.

Mix togeather ingredients and dot with butter.

Bake 40 to 50 min. or until crust is brown and juice begins to bubble through slits in crust.
</directions>
        <ingredients>6 C. tart Apples
3/4 to 1 C. sugar
2 Tbl. Flour
dash salt
1 tsp. cinnamon
1/4 nutmeg
top with butter</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>7</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Apple Pie</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Put a large baking sheet in middle of oven and preheat oven to 425F.

Whisk together flour, zest, cinnamon, allspice, salt, and 2/3 cup sugar 
and gently toss with apples and lemon juice.

Roll out 1 piece of dough (keep remaining piece chilled) on a lightly 
floured surface with a lightly floured rolling pin into a 13-inch round, 
then fit into a 9-inch (4-cup) glass or metal pie plate. Trim edge, 
leaving a 1/2-inch overhang. Chill shell while rolling out dough for top 
crust.

Roll out remaining piece of dough on lightly floured surface with 
lightly floured rolling pin into an 11-inch round.

Spoon filling into shell, then cover with pastry round and trim with 
kitchen shears, leaving a 1/2-inch overhang. Press edges together, then 
crimp decoratively. Lightly brush top of pie with egg and sprinkle all 
over with remaining tablespoon sugar. Cut 3 steam vents in top crust 
with a small sharp knife.

Bake pie on hot baking sheet 20 minutes. Reduce oven temperature to 
375F and continue to bake until crust is golden and filling is 
bubbling, about 40 minutes more. Cool pie to warm or room temperature on 
a rack, 2 to 4 hours.

Makes 6 to 8 serving
</directions>
        <ingredients>3 tablespoons all-purpose flour
1 teaspoon finely grated fresh lemon zest 
1/2 teaspoon cinnamon
1/4 teaspoon ground allspice
1/8 teaspoon salt
2/3 cup plus 1 tablespoon sugar
2 1/2 lb apples, peeled, cored, and each cut into 10 wedges
1 tablespoon fresh lemon juice
Pastry dough
1 large egg, lightly beaten</ingredients>
        <occasion>Party</occasion>
        <serves>7</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Argentine Style Beef </name>
        <category>Beef</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>Put the steak in a large plastic food storage bag. Combine the chimichurri and olive oil and pour into the bag. Remove the excess air, seal the bag and place in refrigerator. Marinate overnight.

Heat a gril. Combine the black pepper, red-pepper flakes and sea salt. Remove steak from the marinade and place on the hot grill. Skprinkle with spices, cook for a few minutes, then turn over and sprinkle spices on other side. Cook until well done, turning as needed for even browning, about 12 to 15 minutes total. Transfer to a cutter board, and cut into thin slices. Serve with chimichurri sauce on the side.

Chimichurri Sauce

Process the parsley and garlic in a blender or food processor with a little of the olive oil until very fine. Add the other ingredients and taste for seasoning. The sauce will keep in the refrigerator for about a week.</directions>
        <ingredients>
1 1/2 lbs. sirloin steak
1/4 cu. chimichurri sauce (see below)
1/4 C. Olive oil
1 tsp. freshly ground pepper
1 tsp. red-pepper flakes
1 tsp. sea salt

Chimichurri Sauce(1cup+)
2 C. chopped parsley
6 garlic cloves
1 C. extra-virgin olive oil
1/2 C. sherry vinegar
1 1/2 tsp. sea salt
1 tsp. dried oregano
1 red jalapeno (or other fresh red chile pepper), stemmed, seeded, and chopped
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Arizona Albondigas Soup </name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In a 5 to 6 qt. pan over high heat, combine broth, tomatoes (including juice), 1/2 tsp. oregano and 1/4 tsp. each cumin, garlic powder, and pepper, cover pan and bring to a boil.

Meanwhile, in a bowl, mix beef, rice egg, salt and the remaining oregano, cumin, garlic powder and pepper.

When broth is boiling, drop beef mixture in 1 inch balls into broth. Cover pan, reduce heat, and simmer until rice iand meatballs is tender to bite, about 10 min. Stir in green onions and cilantro. Ladle into soup bowls.</directions>
        <ingredients>4 C. fat-skimmed beef broth
1 can (140z) diced tomatoes
1 tsp. diced oregano
1/2 tsp. ground cumin
1/2 tsp. garlic powder
1/2 tsp. pepper
3/4 lbs. grond lean beef
1/4 c. precooked dried white rice
1 large egg
1/2 tsp. salt
1/2 c. thinly sliced green onion
1/4 c. chopped fresh cilantro</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Asian Chicken Salad with Roasted Peanuts </name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>Asian</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix dressing, cilantro, and ginger in small bowl. Toss spinach, peppers, chicken, and nuts in large bowl with enough dressing mixture to coat. Season to taste with salt and pepper. Divide salad among 4 plates. Top with mango and serve.
</directions>
        <ingredients>Use leftover chicken if you have any on hand, or start with a rotisserie chicken. Be sure to pick up the sliced peppers from the salad bar while you re at the market. Crunchy sesame breadsticks are all you need to complete the meal - except, of course, dessert, which could be pineapple 
slices sprinkled with coconut and broiled.

3/4 cup bottled Asian-style dressing
1/4 cup chopped fresh cilantro
2 tablespoons chopped fresh ginger
1 6-ounce package baby spinach leaves
2 cups mixed sliced red, yellow and green bell peppers
1 2- to 2 1/2-pound rotisserie chicken, meat torn into bite-size pieces 
(about 4 cups) 
1/2 cup honey-roasted peanuts
1 mango, peeled, pitted, sliced
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Asian Cucumber Ribbon Salad </name>
        <category>Appetizer</category>
        <cuisine>Asian</cuisine>
        <directions>Bring vinegar and sugar to a simmer, stirring until sugar is dissolved, then cool to room temperature. Stir in soy sauce and sesame oil.

Cut cucumber lengthwise into 1/8-inch-thick ribbons using a mandoline or other manual slicer. Toss cucumber with dressing and let stand 5 minutes before serving.

Cooks note:
Do not let dressed cucumber salad stand more than 20 minutes before serving, or it will become soggy.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1/4 cup seasoned rice vinegar
1/2 teaspoon sugar
1 teaspoon soy sauce
1/2 teaspoon Asian sesame oil
1 1/2 English cucumbers (1 1/4 lb total), halved crosswise
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Athenos Greek Salad</name>
        <category>Appetizer</category>
        <cuisine>Greek</cuisine>
        <directions>Toss greens, olives, tomatoes, onion and cucumber with dressing. Spoon onto serving platter. Sprinkle with cheese.

Greek Salad Dressing

Mix together and serve with salad
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 pkg. (10 oz) salad greens
1 c. california ripe olives or Greek olives
3 plum tomatoes, cut into wedges
1/2 c. thinly sliced red onion
1/2 medium cucumber, peeled, cut into wedges
Greek Dressing 
1 pkg. (4 oz) crumbled feta cheese

Greek Salad Dressing

1/2 c. Extra virgin olive oil
1/4 c. fresh lemon juice 
1 clove garlic minced
1 tsp. dried oregano leaves
1/4 tsp. pepper
1/2 tsp. salt or to taste</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Aunt Anne's Apple Strudel</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Place flour in mixing bowl, add wet ingredients. With electric mixer on 1 mix to combine. Increase speed to 4 mix 5 min.

Place dough in well oiled pie plate (about 3 Tbsp.oil) turn dough over let rest for 1 hr. in warm place.

Stretch dough on floured work surface. Cut edges of dough if thick. Drizzle dough with butter. Spread apples on half of dough lengthwise. Sprinkle with sugars and cinnamon drizzle with butter.

Place strudel on well buttered baking sheet (not pam...must be butter). Bake at 350 for 45 min or until golden brown.
***amount of sugar depends on how tart the apples are****
</directions>
        <ingredients>Dough

3 C. Flour
1/2 Tsp. Salt
1/3 C. Oil
3/4 C. Warm Water
1 Egg-beaten

Filling

3 + C. Tart Apples
1/2 to 1 C. White Sugar
1/4 to 1/2 C. Brown Sugar
1 Tsp. Cinnamon
1 Egg-Beaten
Butter
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Thanksgiving</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Baba Ghanouj</name>
        <category>Condiment</category>
        <cuisine>Indian</cuisine>
        <directions>Roast eggplants on grill until they are like bags of mush. Halve and scrape out flesh. Place in bowl to allow juice to pool. Discard all juice. Mix eggplant, onion, and parsley in food processer and blend it to a consistency of lumpy oatmeal. Mix tahini, garlic, vinegar, salt, and cayanne in a bowl and mix to paste. Add paste to food processor and blend in. Allow to set for an hour befoe serving.
</directions>
        <ingredients>2 medium eggplants 
2 Tbls fresh lemon juice
2 Tbls red-wine vinegar
6 garlic cloves, finely choppped
1/2 cup well-stirred tahini
1/3 bunch finely chopped parsley
1 medium yellow onion chopped
1 teas salt
1/4 teas cayenne
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Baby Romaine Salad</name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat oven to 350. On large cookie sheet, toast bread slices 10 to 15 min. or until golden brown, turning once halfway through toasting. Cool on wire rack. (May be prepared up to 1 week ahead. Store tightly covered at toom temp). In small bowl, whisk together shallot, garlic, vinegar, mustard, tarragon, salt and pinch of pepper. Add oil in a slow steady stream, whisking constantly, until blended.

When ready to serve salad, preheat broiler. Spread toasts with goat cheese and sprinkle with pepper. Place in broiler about 4 inch from source of heat and broil 1 to 1 1/2 min. or just until cheese is hot.

In large bowl, toss romaine with dressing. Divide salad among 8 plates and arrange 3 toasts on each.
</directions>
        <ingredients>About 1/2 (8oz) loaf French Bread, cut into twenty-four 1/4 inch thick diagonal slices
1 shallot, minced
1 small garlic clove, minced
1 Tbl. plus 1 tsp. white wine vinegar
1 Tbl. Dijon mustard
1 tsp. chopped fresh tarragon leaves
1/4 tsp. salt
coarsely ground black pepper
3 Tbl. olive oil
4 oz. soft, mild goat cheese such as Montrachet
2 bags (5oz) baby romain salad</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Bacn Wrapped Pork with Barbecued Onions</name>
        <category>Pork</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Wrap a strip of bacon around the edges of each pork chop and secure with toothpicks; season on both sides with seasoning. Grill pork over medium heat for 10 minutes, turning once. Saute' onions with barbecue sauce until soft. Place pork and onions on heavy weight foil seal foil, leaving room for air to circulate. Cook dork and onions for 10 minutes more or until pork is cooked through and onions are very soft.
</directions>
        <ingredients>4 stripes bacon
4 boneless pork loin chops (preferably 1" thick)
2 1/2 tsp. dry barbecue seasoning (such as Weber or McCormick brands)
2 medium onions, sliced 1/4" thick
1/2 cup Stubb's Hickory bourbon Bar-B-Q sauce</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Bacon Macaroni and Cheese </name>
        <category>Pasta</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Fry up the bacon until it’s pretty crisp, drain on paper towels and set it aside until it’s cool enough to handle.

While it’s cooking, grate the cheese and put the water on for the pasta.

In a large heavy saucepan, melt the butter over medium heat until it’s nice and bubbly. Stir in the flour and cook for another couple of minutes. Add the milk and continue cooking and stirring until it’s thick and smooth.

As I was doing this, my son (who is the King of Bacon Frying) asked what I wanted to do with the bacon grease. It suddenly dawned on me that I should’ve used the bacon grease instead of butter to add even more yummy bacon flavor. There’s always next time.

Add about half the cheese and a generous amount of black pepper.
Stir over low heat until the cheese is melted. By now the pasta should be about done.
Crumble the bacon.
Drain the pasta and mix it with the cheese sauce.
Pour about a third of the mixture into a large casserole dish.
Add a layer of bacon and cheeses. Repeat with two more layers.
Sprinkle the top with bread crumbs, a little more bacon and a bit more pepper.

Bake at 350 for 20-30 minutes, until it’s nice and bubbly and beginning to brown.
Serve it up and enjoy!</directions>
        <ingredients>Bacon, about a pound
Cheddar Cheese, 2 pounds. I used a mix of White Sharp and regular old Sharp
Butter, 6 tablespoons (or bacon grease)
Flour, 1/2 cup
Milk, 3 1/2 cups
Elbow Macaroni, 1 pound
Black Pepper
Bread Crumbs, I used Panko because it was in the pantry. Any will do. Or make your own.
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Bacon-Wrapped Hot Dogs  </name>
        <category>Pork</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix together the ketchup and mustard in a small bowl. In a separate bowl, mix the sauerkraut with the chopped onion, set aside. Slice open the hot dogs, down the center, lengthwise, forming a deep pocket in each, but not cutting all the way through. Coat the inside of each hot dog with the mustard ketchup mixture.

Place a strip of cheese deep within the pocket of each hot dog. Top with sauerkraut and onions. Encapsulate the cheese at the ends with the sauerkraut mixture as well, so that no cheese is exposed (otherwise it will drip out when cooking).

Wrap a strip of bacon around each stuffed hot dog, securing with toothpicks at each end. Make sure you wrap tight enough so that the stuffing stays in, but not so tight so that when the hot dog expands will cooking the bacon would tear.

Coat your grill surface with vegetable oil so that the hot dogs don't stick. If you have a grill screen (a screen with smaller holes so that small pieces of whatever you're cooking don't fall through the grill), you can use it, just coat it with vegetable oil first and pre-heat for a couple of minutes. Place the stuffed hot dogs on the grill, stuffing side down. Grill for 2 minutes, until the bacon on that side is cooked, turn the hot dogs a quarter turn and grill for a couple more minutes. Continue to grill for a few minutes each on all sides until the bacon is cooked. Cover the grill in between turnings to help with the cooking.

During the last minute of cooking, open up the hot dog buns and place them open-side down on the grill to lightly toast. Remove the hot dogs and buns from the grill. Remove the toothpicks fro the hot dogs, place them in the buns and serve.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 teaspoon ketchup
1 teaspoon Dijon mustard
4 large hot dogs, knockwurst, or kielbasa
1/2 ounce cheddar cheese, cut into long sticks
2 Tbsp chopped onion
1 cup refrigerated sauerkraut, drained, roughly chopped
4 slices bacon
Vegetable oil
4 long hot dog buns</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Baked Banana-stuffed French Toast </name>
        <category>Bread</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Heat oven to 350F. Place 4 pieces of banana on each of 4 bread slices; mash banana on bread. Top with remaining 4 bread slices. Whisk milk, eggs, vanilla extract and cinnamon in glass pie dish. Working in batches, dip bread in egg mixture; let soak 45 seconds on each side.

Spray large nonstick skillet with vegetable oil spray. Heat over medium heat. Working in batches, add French toast to skillet and cook until golden, about 2 minutes per side. Transfer to baking sheet; bake 8 minutes. Transfer to plates. Dust with powdered sugar. Garnish with strawberries. Serve with maple syrup, if desired.</directions>
        <ingredients>4 ripe bananas, peeled, each cut into 4 pieces
8 thin slices light (reduced-fat) mixed-grain bread
1/2 cup nonfat milk
2 large eggs
1 teaspoon vanilla extract
Pinch of ground cinnamon

Nonstick vegetable oil spray
Powdered sugar
8 large strawberries
Pure maple syrup (optional)

Serves 4.
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Baked Potato Kettle Chip Nachos </name>
        <category>Appetizer</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Prepare everything before kick off. Preheat the oven to 400°F and assemble and bake nachos 15 minutes before half-time.

1. Place the peeled and cubed potato in a small sauce pan, and just cover it with cold water and a pinch of salt. Place the lid on the pot, crank the heat up to high, and cook the potatoes until they are fork tender. Make mashed potatoes with butter and milk, season with salt and pepper.

2. For the bacon bits, bake bacon slices until they are firm but not burned or dry. Chop in quarter inch pieces.

3. Fill an oven-safe wide plate with the chips. Dollop with mashed potatoes, then the extra sharp cheddar cheese, then the bacon bits, and lastly the scallions. Do a second layer if you have enough mashed potatoes. Place the plate on a baking sheet, and bake for 10 minutes in the 400°F oven.

4. Lastly, dollop some sour cream over the top of the nachos, and serve straight from the oven.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 seven-ounce bag of kettle-cooked potato chips
2 medium russet potato, peeled, and cut into 1-inch cubes
1/2 cup whole milk
1 tablespoon butter
Salt and pepper
6 strips thick-cut bacon
1 cup grated extra sharp cheddar cheese
2 to 3 scallions, sliced
1/4 cup sour cream</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Baked Snapper with Potatoes, Oregano, and White Wine </name>
        <category>Fish</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat oven to 450f Slightly overlap sliced potatoes in 13x9x2-inch metal baking pan. Mix 1/4 cup oil, garlic, oregano, 1 teaspoon salt, and crushed red pepper in small bowl. Pour over potatoes. Pour wine and 1/4 cup water over potatoes. Cover and bake 20 minutes. Uncover and bake until potatoes are tender, about 35 minutes longer. Place fish atop potatoes. Drizzle with remaning 1/4 cup oil. Sprinkle with salt, pepper, and 2 tablespoons parsley. Bake uncovered until fish is opaque in center, about 18 minutes. Sprinkle with remaining 2 tablespoons parsley and serve.</directions>
        <ingredients>3 russet potatoes (2 1/4 pounds), peeled, cut into scant 1/4 inch-thick rounds 
1/2 cup olive oil 
3 garlic cloves, minced 
1 1/2 tablespoons chopped fresh oregano 
1 teaspoon salt 
1/4 teaspoon dried crushed red pepper 
1/4 cup dry white wine 
1/4 cup water 
4 5 to 6 ounce 3/4 inch-thick red snapper fillets 
4 tablespoons chopped fresh parsley
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Banana Bread</name>
        <category>Bread</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Cream Shortening and sugar. Add eggs and milk. Combine dry ingredients add to sugar mixture. Mix. Pour into greased loaf pan.

Bake 1 hr. @ 350
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 C. Sugar
1/2 C. shortening
2 Eggs
8 Tbs. Buttermilk
pinch Salt
1 3/4 C. Flour
1 Tsp. Baking Soda
2 Ripe Bananas Mashed
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Banana Split Cake</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix graham crumbs, 1/4 cup of the sugar and the butter; press onto bottom of 13x9" pan, freeze 10 min.

Beat cream cheese and remaining 3/4 cup sugar with electric mexer until well blended. Spread carefully over crust; top with pineapple. Slice 4 of the bananas; arrange over pineapple.

Pour milk into large bowl. Add dry pudding mixes. Beat with wire whisk 2 min. or until well blended. Gently stir in 1 cup of the whipped topping; spread over banana layer in pan. Top with remaining 1 cup whipped topping. Refrigerate at lest 5 hrs.

Slice remaining 2 bananas just before serving; arrange over dessert. Sprinkle with pecasn. Store leftovers in refrigerator.
</directions>
        <ingredients>9 Honey Maid Honey Grahams, finely crushed (aout 1 1/2 cups crumbs)
1 cup sugar, divided
1/3 cup butter, melted
2 pkg. (8 oz) cream cheese, softened
1 can (20 oz) crushed pineapple in juice, drained
6 bananas, divided
2 cups cold milk
2 pkg. (4 serving size each) Jell-O vanilla flavor instant pudding
2 cups thawed Cool Whip whipped topping, divided
1 cup chopped peacans</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>12</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Banana-Nut Oat Bran Muffins </name>
        <category>Bread</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Oil 12 muffins cup or line with paper baking cups.

Grate 1 tbl. peel (orange part only) from orange. Cut oranges in half and ream juice. Measure 1/2 c. juice; save remainder for other uses.

In a large bowl, mix cereal, baking powder, salt, and walnuts. Add to egg mixture and stir until evenly moistened. Spoon batter equally into muffin cups.

Bake muffins in a 400 oven until golden brown, 20 to 25 min. Run a knife between muffins and cup sides, invert pan to remove muffins, and set muffins upright on a rack. Serve hot, warm or at room temp.</directions>
        <ingredients>About 2 Tbl. sald oil
2 large eggs
1 C. massed ripe bananas
1/4 c. honey
1/4 c. firmly packed brown sugar
2 C. quick-cooking oat bran cereal
2 tsp. baking powder
1/2 tsp. salt
1/2 c. chopped walnuts</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Basil Scampi Shrimp </name>
        <category>Seafood</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>1. In a 6- to 8-quart pan over high heat, bring about 4 quarts water to a boil; add linguine and cook, stirring occasionally, just until tender to bite, 6 to 8 minutes. Drain pasta, reserving about 1/3 cup cooking liquid; return pasta to pan.

2. Meanwhile, in a 10- to 12-inch frying pan over medium-high heat, melt butter with olive oil. Add shrimp, garlic, chili flakes, pepper, and 1/4 teaspoon salt; stir for 2 minutes. Add wine; stir often until shrimp are 
opaque but still moist-looking in center of thickest part (cut to test), 3 to 4 minutes longer. Stir in basil.

3. Pour shrimp mixture into pan with cooked pasta; mix gently. If mixture is too dry, add reserved pasta-cooking liquid. Divide evenly among four wide, shallow bowls. Add salt to taste.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 pound dried linguine
1/4 cup (1/8 lb.) butter
2 tablespoons olive oil
1 1/2 pounds shrimp (35 to 40 per lb.), peeled (tails left on), 
deveined, and rinsed
2 tablespoons minced garlic
3/4 teaspoon hot chili flakes
1/4 teaspoon fresh-ground pepper
About 1/4 teaspoon salt
1 cup dry white wine
2 cups lightly packed fresh basil leaves, slivered (see notes)</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Bavarian Potato Salad </name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>German</cuisine>
        <directions>Place the potatoes and stock in a small saucepan and bring to a simmer. Cook until the potatoes are tender but still retain their shape. Drain the stock, reserving some.

While the potatoes are cooking crisp the bacon in a skillet. When it is browned and crunchy pour off and reserve the bacon fat. Reserve the crisp bacon.

Whisk together until smooth the lemon juice, sugar, Dijon and 4 tablespoons of the warm bacon fat. Toss with the potatoes, onions, crisp bacon and parsley. Add a bit of the reserved chicken broth to moisten if needed. Season to taste with salt and pepper. Cover and let rest for two hours at room temperature before serving.
</directions>
        <ingredients>4 cup potato, peeled, and, sliced, 1/4 inch thick
2 cup chicken broth
1 cup bacon, chopped
1/2 cup onion, minced
1 tsp sugar
2 tbsp lemon juice
1 tbsp Dijon mustard
1/2 cup chopped Italian flat-leaf parsley
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Beef and Black bean Sup </name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>Cuban</cuisine>
        <directions>Heat oil in a large stock pot. Add beef and brown aon all sides. Add remaining ingredients except beans and bring to a boil. Reduce heat and simmer, covered, for 1 1/2 hrs. Stir in beans and cook for 10 min. more, Serve with assorted sliced breads, corn muffins, flour tortillas or breadsticks.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 Tbsp. EVOO
1 lb. London Broil, diced
1 large onion, peeled and chopped
1 (14.5 oz) can diced tomatoes
1 (12 oz) tomato paste
1 (7oz) can diced green chiles
4 cups beef stock
1 cup each; sliced carrots, celery and frozen or cnned corn
3 to 4 tsp. Morton &amp; Bassett Mexican Blend Seasoning
1 (15 oz) can black beans, rinsed and drained</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>10</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Beef with Asparagus </name>
        <category>Beef</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In a medium bowl combine ginger, wine, soy sauce, and sesame oil. Toss beef strips in soy mixture; marinate for 30 min. to several hrs.

Drain beef well and reserve marinade. Combine marinade with enough water to make 1/3 cup. Dissolve cornstarch in this mixture.

Heat wok over high heat and add 1 Tblp. of the oil. Add beef to pan; sir-fry until meat loses the the raw color (about 1 min.). Remove meat from pan.

Add remaining oil to wok. Add asparagus and stir-fry over medium heat until just heated through. Return beef to pan; add reserved marinade. Increase heat to high and cook until sauce thickens. Serve immediately.

Variation: When asparagus in not in season, broccoli can be used.
</directions>
        <ingredients>
2 tsp. minced fresh ginger
2 Tblp. Shaoxing wine or dry sherry
3 Tblp.soy sauce
1/2 tsp. sesame oil
1/2 lb. lean beef, thinly sliced into strips
1 1/2 tsp. cornstarch
2 to 3 Tblp. vegetable oil
1 lb. asparagus, cut diaponally into 2 inch pieces</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Beef-Ale Stew and Green-Onion Buttermilk Dumplings </name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In large bowl, toss beef with 3 tbsp flour, 1 tsp salt, and pepper. In large pot, heat 1 tbsp vegetable oil over medium-high heat. Add enough beef to pot to form single layer (about 3 of total), being careful not to overcrowd. Brown meat on all sides, about 7 minutes. Transfer to large bowl and brown remaining beef in similar batches. If meat or pan juices start to scorch, reduce heat.

Add 1 bottle ale to pot, scraping up brown bits with wooden spoon. Pour ale over beef and return empty pot to medium-high heat. Add remaining tbsp oil to pot. Add onions and 2 tsp salt. Cook, stirring often, 2 minutes. Cover pot, reduce heat to low. Cook, stirring occasionally, until onions have hint of gold color, about 20 minutes. Remove lid, raise heat to medium-high, stir in 3 tbsp flour. Cook, stirring often, 3 minutes. Add mushrooms, reserved beef and ale, remaining bottle of ale, and carrots. Bring to boil. Cover and lower heat to gentle simmer. Cook, stirring occasionally, until beef is tender, about 3 hours.

About 40 minutes before serving, make dumplings. In medium bowl, stir together remaining 2 cups flour, green onions, remaining f tsp salt, baking soda. Using pastry blender or your fingers, work cold butter into flour mixture until it resembles cornmeal with some pea-size pieces. In another bowl, wisk together buttermilk and egg. Gently fold wet ingredients into dry, mixing until a very shaggy dough forms. If more liquid is needed, add additional buttermilk 1 tbsp at a time. Gently form dough into 12 equally sized balls and drop into stew for final 20 to 30 minutes or until dumplings are fluffy and cooked through. Let sit 15 minutes before serving; stew will thicken as it cools</directions>
        <ingredients>4 lbs beef chuck, trimmed of excess fat and cut into 1 1/2-inch pieces
2 cups plus 6 tbsp flour 
3 3/4 tsp salt
1 tsp freshly ground black pepper
2 tbsp vegetable oil
2 bottles (12 oz each) ale
2 large onions, thinly sliced
8 oz mushrooms, trimmed and quartered
3 large carrots, peeled, halved lengthwise,and cut into 1-inch pieces
5 cup thinly sliced green onions (green part only)
5 tsp baking soda
4 1/2 tbsp cold butter, cut into small pieces
About 3/4 cup buttermilk
1 egg
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Beef-Fajitas with Black Beans </name>
        <category>Beef</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>Marinade

Combine marinade ingredients in a shallow dish. Turn flank steak in marinade and let stand 15 minutes. The meat can be placed in marinade in the morning and allowed to marinate until suppertime if you enjoy very strong, spicy flavors. The short marinade will result in a milder tasting meat which is more palatable to many not-too-hot taste buds.

Follow directions on packaged rice and get it simmering, it will take 18 to 20 minutes

Heat a grill pan to high heat and sear the flank steak 4 minutes on each side. Reduce heat and cook meat 6 to 8 minutes longer, turning occasionally.

Heat a medium nonstick skillet over high heat. Blister tortillas 30 seconds on each side and stack them on a plate. Loosely wrap tortillas with foil and place them on the dinner table. Add oil to hot pan and sear sliced peppers and onions for fajitas. Season peppers and onions with salt and pepper. Char edges and stir-fry the peppers and onions 
until just tender, 2 or 3 minutes. Transfer to a platter and cover with loose foil to keep hot. Add another tablespoon oil, garlic, jalapeno and chopped onion; saute for 2 minutes. Add black beans and spices to the pan and heat through for another 1 to 2 minutes. Transfer beans to a 
serving dish. Top beans with cilantro and scallions.

Remove meat from grill pan and let it rest 5 minutes for juices to distribute. Transfer peppers and onions to grill to get the sizzle effect going. Slice meat very thin on an angle against the grain. Pile meat on top of cooked peppers and onions and take the hot grill to the table, letting rest on trivets or a cool wire rack. Stack meat and veggies in warm tortillas and enjoy with a side of spicy black beans.</directions>
        <ingredients>2/3 cup Mexican beer
1/2 cup chopped chipotle in adobo sauce, found on international foods 
aisle, smoky chipotle prepared salsa may be substituted
1 lime, juiced
Several sprigs fresh thyme, chopped, about 2 tablespoons
1 1/2 tablespoons (1/2 palmful) chili powder
A generous drizzle vegetable, corn, or olive oil

Fajitas:
Flank steak
8 (8-inch) flour tortillas
1 tablespoon vegetable, corn or olive oil
1 large red bell pepper, seeded and cut into strips 
1 poblano pepper (if you market does not carry them, substitute 1 
Cubanelle long Italian pepper)
1 medium yellow-skinned Spanish onion, cut into thin strips
Salt and pepper

1 package Spanish style rice, any brand, prepared to directions on the 
package

Black Beans: 
1 tablespoon (1 turn around the pan) vegetable, olive, or corn oil
3 cloves garlic, chopped
1 jalapeno, seeded and finely chopped
1 small white onion
1 large can black beans, drained and rinsed
1 teaspoon ground cumin
Salt and pepper
Chopped cilantro and sliced scallions, for garnish, optional</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Beer Bread</name>
        <category>Bread</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix flour, yeast, beer, water.
Add starter, scrap, and DME
Ferment until doubled.
Shape, fold in 5 min. and place in conche lined bowl, proof, and bake in oven preheated to 450 reduced to 425 for 20 min. Rotate and continue to bake until internal temp is 200-207 degrees.

Used Redhook ESB, will try RubyRed or Red Tail Ale next. No lagers or whit beers.

Firm starter is biga. 4 oz sourdough starter, 8 oz water, 14 oz bread flour.

Scrap is 1.5 oz flour, 1 oz water, .1 oz yeast
</directions>
        <ingredients>% oz
66.6 Unbleached flour 10.6
20.9 whole wheat flour 3.42
12.5 Rye flour 1.6
8.0 DME 1.28
0.1 yeast 0.16
66 firm starter 10.5
25 scrap 1.9
50 beer 9.5
2 salt 2</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Beer Cheese Soup </name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Slowly add chicken broth and cream to flour mixture, add cheese whiz. Stir over medium heat until the cheese is melted
add other ingredents and simmer for fifteen minutes
serve with popcorn (in the soup)</directions>
        <ingredients>Beer Cheese Soup

1/2 cup of softened butter
1 cup of flour, blend flour and butter to a smooth paste
4 cups of chicken broth
1 1/2 cups of cream or half and half
1- 6oz jar of cheese whiz
1 stale can of beer, do not need the full can. (sip for the cook)
1 tblsp worch. sauce
1/4 cup of chives
1/4 cup of chopped onions
optional 1/2 teaspoon yellow food coloring</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Beer Sausages, Peppers, and Onions on the Grill </name>
        <category>Beef</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Sear sausages in cast iron pan with oil.
Move to grill in indirect heat for 10 minutes to cook.
Add onions and peppers to pan with more oil.
Saute vegetables by adding beer to steam them.
Move sasuages to pan and cook covered for 10 more minutes.
Serve on rolls.
</directions>
        <ingredients>10 mild Italian sausages
4 green bell peppers cut in thick strips
1 large yellow onion
2 mild green peppers
rools, not hot dog buns.
Olive oil
Beer</ingredients>
        <occasion>Summer</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Beer batter for fish</name>
        <category>Fish</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix together let rest 1/2 hr. before frying.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 c. flour
1 tsp. baking powder
1 tsp. salt
1 tsp. paprika
1 egg
1 c. beer-can open let set out for awhile</ingredients>
        <occasion>Summer</occasion>
        <serves>12</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Benedetti Italian Meat Sauce </name>
        <category>Sauce</category>
        <cuisine>Indian</cuisine>
        <directions>Benedetti Italian Meat Sauce

Things to keep in mind... fresh, complex 
Yield: Approx. 2 gallons This sauce gets better as it sits. It freezes and cans very well, although I prefer freezing. 
3 lbs. Ground Meat ( italian sausage, beef, pork, veal, turkey are all fine... try to use two (or more) different types if you can) brown meat, drain (if desired) and set aside1-2 onions garlic parsley other herbs and spices... don t be shy. The sauce is hearty and lends itself well to experimentation and extra spice! Use your favorites, and, of 
course, include oregano.sautee in olive oil, add browned meat. In large simmering pot add to the meat mixture... 
tomatoes... This is the bulk of the liquid, so use as 
much as would like to have. Canned are fine. Use a combination of paste, sauce, whole, stewed, and/or crushed, not to mention fresh use at least one can of whole, stewed, 
or fresh for the extra liquid they provide. stock... 1 quart(?) homeade is best, Better-Than-Boullion (a refrigerated concentrate) is good, canned stock or boullion cubes will suffice. Use chicken, beef, vegetable, etc. I usually use chicken. dry red wine... I use the cheapest I can find... Save the good stuff for drinking:)Optional fresh ingredient suggestions mushrooms zucchini carrot 
Buon appetito!

Michael Benedetti</directions>
        <ingredients></ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Berry Squares </name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Arrange cade slices on bottom of 13x9 inch dish, cutting to fit if necessary; drizzle with juice. Top with berries; sprinkle with sugar.

Pour milk into large bowl. Add dry pudding mixes. Beat with wire whisk 2 min. Gently stir in 1 cup on the whipped topping; spread over berries. Top with remaining whipped topping.

Refrigerate at least 1 hr. before serving. Store leftovers in refrigerator.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 Pkg. (12 oz) pound cake, cut into 10 slices
3 Tbsp. orange juice
4 C. fresh berries (halved strawberries, raspberries and blueberries
2 Tbsp. sugar
2 1/2 c. cold milk
2 pkg. (4 serving size each) Jell-O French Vanilla Flavor instant Pudding &amp; Pie Filling
1 tub (8 oz) Cool Whipped topping thawed, divided</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>12</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Best Pesto Ever</name>
        <category>Sauce</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Pick through the basil saving only the leaves. Throw away any stems, flowers, and bad spots. I aim for a colander full of crisp green leaves. Wash them and dry. You can squeeze handfuls of basil to get the water out or use a salad spinner, towel, etc. Once dried, put it into the food processor bowl.

Peel the garlic and add it to the food processor bowl. I wouldn't use less than 3 cloves and if you're a garlic fan, you can use as much as a full bulb. Here's an easy way to peel garlic: Put your palm on top of a clove. Push down on the back of that hand with your other hand until you feel the clove underneath "give". Now pick up your hand, the skin will peel right off the clove. You can peel a full bulb in 30 seconds this way.

If you add a lot of garlic, you're going to want to add some parsley too. Parsley keeps you from stinking after you eat garlic. Toss a handful of parsley into the processor bowl.

If you've got health restrictions or dietary preferences, you don't have to use butter, but I find a little bit gives the pesto a creamy consistency that is really luxurious. Take 1/2 a stick of butter and melt it in the microwave or by some other method. If you don't want to use butter, add 1/4 cup of olive oil instead.

To the melted butter add 1/2 cup of olive oil. You can use really find olive oil here, because we're not going to be heating it.

Turn on the food processor and drizzle in the butter and oil. Grind the basil, garlic, and parsley until it is totally smooth and no pieces of basil remain. I usually stop the food processor 4 or 5 times to scrape the sides with a spatula, then grind some more.

Now add the grated parmesan to the food processor bowl. Use just 4 or 5 quick pulses to mix in the cheese without chopping it further. The chunky consistency of the pesto is one of its best features.

Add the pine nuts and pulse another 5 or 6 times. Aim to chop the nuts some but not pulverize them.
</directions>
        <ingredients>basil - a large colander full
3 cloves - 1 bulb garlic
1/4 lb good parmesan cheese
1/2 stick (2 oz) butter
1/2 c extra virgin olive oil
parsley - optional, to offset garlic breath
salt/pepper
1/2 c pine (pignola) nuts

1 ice cube tray (for freezing)</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Bing Cherry Pie</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix first three ingredients together. Add cherries and almond extract together. Top with pieces of butter.

Put in unbaked pie shell. Top with crust.

Bake 450-15min
325-20-25 min. longer</directions>
        <ingredients>1/4 c. flour
3/4 c. to 1 c. sugar
1/16 tsp salt
3 c. pitted cherries
4 drops almond extract
1 T. butter- (top of mixture)
2 Unbaked pie shells</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Black Bean and Mushroom Burgers</name>
        <category>Vegetable</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>
1. Prepare a medium-hot fire in the grill with a lightly-oiled vegetable grill rack in place.

2. Heat the oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Add the onion and cook, stirring, until golden, about 4 minutes. Add the mushrooms, garlic, and cumin and cook, stirring, until the mushrooms have released their juices, about 5 minutes.

3. Spoon the mixture into the food processor. Add the beans and cilantro and process briefly until well combined but still chunky. Spoon into a bowl, stir in the goat cheese, if using, and bread crumbs. Season generously with salt and pepper.

4. With wet hands, form the mixture into 6 burgers. Mist both sides with nonstick spray.

5. Grill the burgers until crisp and heated through, about 5 minutes per side.

6. Serve the burgers on the buns, passing salsa at the table.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 tablespoon olive or canola oil
1 onion, finely chopped
8 ounces mushrooms, finely chopped
2 garlic cloves, minced
1/2 teaspoon ground cumin
1 1/2 cups cooked black beans (or 1 15-ounce can, drained)
1/2 cup packed fresh cilantro leaves
2 ounces soft goat cheese, crumbled (optional)
4 slices stale or toasted sandwich bread, processed to make bread crumbs
Salt and black pepper, to taste
6 hamburger buns or hard rolls
Salsa</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Black Olive Tapenade </name>
        <category>Condiment</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>Don't be to fussy about exact quantities. Blend the ingredients in a kitchen processor, but don't overdo it, some texture is good. Keep back some of the oil and adjust the acid oil balance at the end.

Some variations. You can use a little English mustard to warm things up. You can use red wine vinegar instead of the lemon juice. A teaspoon of horseradish will add just another layer of complexity to the flavour.

Serving. Just spread it onto some French stick sliced into rounds. For a real indulgence you can spread some lightly toasted ciabacca bread with a soft goat cheese. Then spread on some tapenade and top with slices of ripe tomato and maybe a fresh basil leaf. I also enjoy a sandwich made with ripe tomatoes and tapenade between slices of white Italian bread.

A generous spoon of tapenade can enliven a meal of grilled or steamed fish. Or perhaps you can stir it through some freshly cooked pasta like you would use pesto.

This sharp, salty and savory delight just cries out for a full flavoured dry rose, say one made from Grenache. Or you could try a bold dry white wine such as Vermentino, or even a cool light bodied red wine.

Tapenade will keep in a jar in the fridge for a couple of weeks in the unlikely event that you don't eat it all at once.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 cup of pitted black olives, kalamata are fine
2 tablespoons of pickled capers, drained
1 tablespoons of seed mustard
4 cloves of crushed garlic
6 anchovy fillets in oil
2 tablespoons of chopped fresh herbs, thyme is best but you can use say parsley or marjoram
2 tablespoons of Brandy or dry sherry
A grind or two of black pepper
juice of a half of lemon
4 tablespoons of olive oil
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Black Pepper Pasta with Shrimp and Garlic Cream Sauce </name>
        <category>Seafood</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Basic 2lb pasta recipe with up to 1/4 cup fresh ground pepper that passes through pasta machine die.

Saute garlic and onion in 1/4 c olive oil. 
Deglaze with white wine, add herbs, cook to reduce to syrupy essence.
Add black pepper pasta to boiling salted water.
Make rue from butter and flour and add with cream to pan. Cook until thinkened.
Add sauce and drained pasta back into hot pasta pot.
Heat 2T olive oil, and cook shrimp until slightly orange but not fully done. 
Immediately add to pasta and sauce and stir. Move to warmed serving bowl.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1/4 cup olive oil, plus 2 tablespoons
5 cloves garlic, finely chopped
4 cloves shallots, chopped
2 cups white wine
2 tablespoons chopped fresh parsley leaves
2 tablespoons chopped fresh basil leaves, plus sprigs for garnish
1 teaspoon chopped thyme leaves
2 cups 1/2&amp;1/2 cream, butter, flour
1 1/2 pounds (21/25 count) shrimp peeled and deveined 
grated parmesan cheese
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Blackened Red Snapper </name>
        <category>Fish</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Take well-seasoned cast iron skillet and place over high heat. Skillet must be white-hot before adding fish.

In a flat container or plate, combine 1 teaspoon onion powder, 1 teaspoon garlic powder, 1 teaspoon cayenne pepper, 3/4 teaspoon white pepper, 3/4 teaspoon black pepper, 1/2 teaspoon paprika, 1/2 teaspoon dried thyme leaves, 1/2 teaspoon dried oregano leaves and 1/2 teaspoon dried basil leaves. Mix well. Set aside.

Slice 4 fresh tomatoes and arrange on serving plate. Set aside.

Dredge each filet into melted butter and then coat with spice mixture. Carefully place in cast iron skillet and sear until blackened, about 2 minutes. Flip fish over and blacken other side. Place fish on tomatoes and top with a dollop of sour cream.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 tsp. onion powder
1 tsp. garlic powder
1 tsp. cayenne pepper
3/4 tsp. white pepper
3/4 tsp. black pepper
1/2 tsp. paprika
1/2 tsp. dried thyme leaves
1/2 tsp. dried oregano leaves
1/2 tsp. dried basil leaves
4 Tbs. melted butter
Two 6 to 8 oz. red snapper filets, 1/2 to 3/4-inches thick
4 fresh tomatoes, your favorite
Chives and basil to garnish
2 Tbs. sour cream</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Blueberry Buttermilk </name>
        <category>Other</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>1. In a bowl, mix flour, baking soda, baking powder, and salt. In a small bowl, whisk eggs, buttermilk, and butter until blended. Stir egg mixture into flour mixture, then gently stir in blueberries.

2. Place a nonstick griddle or a 12-inch nonstick frying pan over medium heat3(50). When hot, coat griddle lightly with oil and adjust heat to maintain temperature (see The perfect pancake). Spoon batter in 1/3-cup portions onto griddle and cook until pancakes are browned on the 
bottom and edges begin to look dry, about 2 minutes; turn with a wide spatula and brown other sides, 1 1/2 to 2 minutes longer. Coat pan with more oil as necessary to cook remaining pancakes.

3. Serve pancakes as cooked, or keep warm in a single layer on baking sheets in a 200 oven for up to 15 minutes.
</directions>
        <ingredients>PREP AND COOK TIME: About 30 minutes

NOTES: For consistency, cooks at Marston s prefer canned Maine blueberries in syrup; we like fresh blueberries in their batter too. Serve these pancakes with butter and warm maple syrup.

MAKES: About 20 pancakes; 5 to 6 servings
2 cups all-purpose flour
1 1/2 teaspoons baking soda
1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder
1/2 teaspoon salt
2 large eggs
2 1/2 cups buttermilk
1/4 cup (1/8 lb.) butter or margarine, melted
1 cup fresh blueberries, rinsed and drained, or canned blueberries, 
drained (see notes)
Salad oil</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Brazilian Pork </name>
        <category>Pork</category>
        <cuisine>Other</cuisine>
        <directions>Pat pork chops dry with paper towels. In cup, mix cumin, coriander, thyme, all-spice and 1/4 tsp. salt. Rub pork cps with spice mixture.

Heat nonstick 12" skillet over medium-high heat until hot. Add pork chops and cook 4 minutes; turn pork over and cook 3 to 4 min. longer, until lightly browned on the outside and still slightly pink on the inside. Transfer pork to platter; cover with foil to keep warm.

In same skillet, heat olive oil over medium heat. Add onion and cook, stirring frequently, 5 minutes or until golden. Add garlic and cook 1 minute longer, stirring.

Add beans, chicken broth, lime juice, pepper, and remaining 1/4 tsp. salt; heat through.

To serve, spook bean mixure over pork; sprinkle iwth cilanro. Serve with orange wedges if you like.
</directions>
        <ingredients>4 boneless pork loin chops, 3/4" thick (5 oz) each
1/2 tsp. ground cumin
1/2 tsp. ground coriander
1/4 tsp. dried thyme
1/8 tsp. ground allspice
1/2 tsp. salt
1 tsp. olive oil
1 med. onion, chopped
3 garlic cloves, crushed with garlic press
1 can (15 to 19 oz) black beans, rinsed and drained
1/2 c. chicken broth
1 tbsp. fresh lime juice
1/4 tsp. coarsely ground black pepper
1/4 c. packed fresh cilantro, chopped 
fresh orange wedges, optional</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Brined Roast Turkey </name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Make Brine:

Combine all brine ingredients except ice water in a pot or pan and bring to a boil.

Stir to dissolve solids and then remove from heat.

Allow it to cool to room temperature, then refrigerate until Thoroughly Chilled.

Brine yer bird:

With a fully-thawed bird, you are now ready to brine. You can do this the night before you plan to bake your bird.

The great thing about a brine is it doesn't make the meat taste salty. That's because the salted water (infused with your added flavors) will begin penetrating the meat as soon as you dunk it. After a few hours, the salt will reach equilibrium, meaning no more salt will be added to the bird from the brine. At that point, leaving the bird in the drink won't make it any saltier.

Clean your sink thoroughly. I use a product called Greased Lightning to remove any gunk. Then I use soap and water and finish with a light bleach spray to sterilize. Then rinse completely.

Set the turkey in the sink and open the sack up. At either end you'll find a bag of goodies. I freeze this and use it later for turkey broth. You can discard it if you prefer. Don't leave these bags in the bird!

Your turkey may also come with a wire leg holder to keep the legs together. It can be tough to remove, so be gentle.

Rinse the turkey inside and out.

Now for the brine...

Drop some ice cubes into the bucket to make it easier to set the turkey down.

Then place the bird in the bucket breast-down.

Pour in the brine. I used a ladle to keep down the mess.

Add ice and top off with water.

The cavity of the turkey should also fill up with brine, so you might have to jiggle the turkey to get it to fill up.

Cap the bucket and put it in a cool place for 6 to 8 hours.

Ready to Bake...@ 500F!
Take your turkey out of the brine and discard the brine. Rinse the turkey inside and out, and then dry using paper towels inside and out.

Take this time to form the aluminum triangle to the breast meat. Set that aside.

Move the rack in your oven to its lowest position and set to 500F. That's right...500F.

For the aromatics...combine apple, onion, cinnamon stick, rosemary and sage in a microwave safe container. Add a bit of water and nuke it for 5 minutes on high while you do the next steps.

Break or roughly chop the old vegetables (celery, carrot, onion) and cover the bottom of your roasting pan. This keeps your turkey off the bottom of the pan. If you have a rack that fits the roaster, you can use that instead.

Add a little water to the pan (this step will prevent oil from burning during the 500F phase, and won't steam the bird at all).

Set the bird on a nonslip surface (in the roaster is ok, but I happen to have a plastic tray and paper towels instead). Trim off the neck and tail fat. These can go into turkey broth later, but will burn if not trimmed now.

Now lift up the wing and tuck it under (see pictures). This helps the gobbler sit in the roaster.

Coat the entire outside of the bird with canola oil. Don't be chicken--just use your hands like I did.

Use tongs to stuff the cavity with your steamed aromatics.

Bake your Tom Turkey for 30 minutes at 500F. This will make him brown up nicely! If you get any smoking, turn on your blower or open some windows. But you shouldn't if you added the water like I said ;)

Remove, Probe, ReLoad...Eat!
After 30 minutes, the turkey is ready to come out...so he can go right back in.

Lower temp to 350F.

Insert the probe thermometer in the thickest part of the turkey breast. Be careful not to hit bone. If you do, just back out a little bit (don't make a bunch of holes!).

Set the thermometer to alarm at 161F.

Carefully cover the breast with the aluminum foil triangle...don't burn yourself!

Return the turkey to the oven, minding the probe cable--don't crimp it.

If you don't have a probe, a 14 to 16 lb bird will take about 2 1/2 hours to bake. Use an instant read thermometer to take the temperature of the thick part of the breast after that time. If it's at 160ish, pull it out.

Let the turkey rest for 15 minutes before carving. Do Not pull out that stupid popup timer before then!

Bon apetit!</directions>
        <ingredients>Turkey:
1 turkey (up to 16lbs)
Canola Oil
various old vegetables* (carrots, onions, celery) to line bottom of roasting pan

*If you don't have old veggies, just get a rack for your roasting pan instead.

Brine:
1 Cup kosher salt
1/2 Cup light brown sugar
1 gal *stock
*I made a combination of beef and chicken stock, and apple juice because it was what I had available. You can use these, as well as vegetable broth and other juices that aren't too sweet (i.e. don't use grape or Kool Aid :) The beef stock doesn't harm the flavor.
1/2 tablespoon black peppercorns (or same amount of ground if you have that)
1/2 tablespoon green peppercorns (optional, just add more black pepper if you don't have this)
1/2 tablespoon allspice berries (optional)
1 gallon water + ice

Aromatics (don't do this prep until the day of the baking!):
1 red apple, sliced (gala is nice)
1/2 med onion, sliced (yellow or white is good)
1 cinnamon stick (broken into smaller pieces)
1 Cup water
4 sprigs rosemary (fresh is best)
6 leaves sage (fresh is best, but I only had dry)</ingredients>
        <occasion>Thanksgiving</occasion>
        <serves>10</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Broiled Spiced Pork Chops</name>
        <category>Pork</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In a small bowl stir together the salt, the cinnamon, the allspice, the cloves, and pepper to taste. Pat the pork chops dry with paper towels, rub the spice mixture on both sides of them, and chill the chops, covered, for 30 minutes. Broil the chops on the oiled rack of a broiler pan under a preheated broiler about 4 inches from the heat for 5 minutes on each side, or until they are cooked through.
</directions>
        <ingredients>Can be prepared in 45 minutes or less.

1/4 teaspoon salt
1/8 teaspoon cinnamon
1/8 teaspoon ground allspice
a pinch of ground cloves
two 1/2-inch-thick loin pork chops</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Brownies w/white Chocolate</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat oven to 325F. Butter 8-inch square baking pan. Stir chocolate and butter in heavy medium saucepan over low heat until melted and smooth. Cool to room temperature.

Combine 2/3 cup flour, 1/2 teaspoon baking powder and 1/4 teaspoon salt in small bowl. Whisk 1 cup sugar, eggs and vanilla extract in medium bowl until mixture is very thick, about 3 minutes. Whisk in melted chocolate mixture, then flour mixture. Stir in white chocolate. Transfer 
to prepared pan.

Bake brownies until tester inserted into center comes out with moist 
crumbs attached, about 28 minutes. Transfer brownies in pan to rack; 
cool completely. (Can be prepared 1 day ahead. Store airtight at room 
temperature.)

Cut brownies into 16 squares. Serve brownies with strawberries.
</directions>
        <ingredients>4 ounces unsweetened chocolate, coarsely chopped
6 tablespoons (3/4 stick) unsalted butter

2/3 cup all purpose flour
1/2 teaspoon baking powder
1/4 teaspoon salt
1 cup sugar
2 large eggs
1 teaspoon vanilla extract
5 ounces good-quality white chocolate (such as Lindt or Baker s), cut 
into 1/2-inch pieces

Fresh large strawberries
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Brunch Casserole</name>
        <category>Breakfast</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat oven to 350.
Chop ham into cubes, set aside. Wisk eggs until light lemon-colored. Add flour and wisk until combined (flour may remain lumpy-that's okay). Add remaining ingredients. Pour into well-greased 9X13 casserole dish.
Bake 45 minutes until browned and knife inserted in center comes out clean. Let rest for 10 minutes. Cut into squares and serve. Serves 10-16, depending on size of servings.

Notes:
Recipe calls for 2 cups chopped green chiles. This seemed like a lot to me, so I
added one small can of Ortega chiles. It gives it just the right amount of kick. Or
substitute pepper jack cheese for some or all of the jack cheese.
This recipe can easily be halved, using a 6 X 9 casserole dish. Bake about 40
minutes.
If you prefer, use sausage instead of ham. Or, omit the meat completely. You can
add mushrooms, green onions, or just about anything else you like.
To cut the fat, use reduced fat cottage cheese and jack cheese. You could also
substitute reduced fat margarine for the butter.
I have experimented using a mix of cheddar and jack cheese, and it was equally
good.</directions>
        <ingredients>10 eggs
!/2 cup flour
1/2 tsp. Salt (I omit the salt when using ham, otherwise it's too salty)
4 Tb. Butter, melted
1 pint cottage cheese, small curd
1 tsp. Baking powder
16 oz. Monterey jack cheese, shredded
1 Ib. Ham, thickly sliced
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Bruschetta Pomodoro (Tomato Bruschetta)</name>
        <category>Appetizer</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>let stand ... approximately 1/2 hour

serve over crostini (toasted sliced bread) drizzled liberally with 
olive oil

</directions>
        <ingredients>tomatoes finely chopped
olive oil
garlic
salt and pepper
add fresh herbs (finely chopped) if desired
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Buckwheat Pancakes with Orange Butter</name>
        <category>Breakfast</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Orange Butter

Beat the butter with the brown sugar until it's soft and creamy. Beat in the orange zest and orange juice until light. Serve with warm pancakes.

Buckwheat Pancakes

1. Whisk the dry ingredients to combine in a medium bowl. In a smaller bowl, lightly beat the egg with the molasses, and then whisk in the buttermilk and melted butter.

2. Form a well in the center of the dry ingredients and pour in the wet. Stir together quickly, just until the dry ingredients are moistened.

3. Spray hot griddle with cooking oil. Spoon batter on in 1/4-cup dollops. Cook until bubbles begin to form around the edges, 2 to 3 minutes, adjusting the heat as necessary to keep pancakes from scorching or cooking too slowly. When the cakes are just beginning to set, flip to finish cooking on the second side, about 1 minute more. I found that they tended to stay raw and needed a little extra cooking to suit my taste.

4. Serve immediately with orange butter.

</directions>
        <ingredients>Orange Butter

8 tablespoons unsalted butter, softened
2 tablespoon packed brown sugar
Zest of 1 orange
1-2 tablespoon orange juice

Buckwheat Pancakes (makes twenty 3 1/2-inch pancakes)

Ingredients

1 cup (4 1/4 ounces) whole buckwheat flour
3/4 cup (3 1/8 ounces) unbleached all-purpose flour
2 teaspoons baking powder
1 teaspoon baking soda
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 egg
2 tablespoons molasses
2 cups buttermilk
1 tablespoon unsalted butter, melted</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Buffalo Chicken Wings</name>
        <category>Appetizer</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Remove the tips from the wings. Discard or save for stock. Cut the rest in half at the join. Dry thouroughly on paper towels.

Grill wings until almost cooked. Soak in sauce for 3 to 4 min. Grill to cook wings fully.

Make sauce by melting butter with hot sauce and vinegar.
</directions>
        <ingredients>20 Chicken Wings
4 Tbl. butter
5 Tbl. Durkee s Louisana Hot Sauce
1 Tbl. White vinegar
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Bulgur Salad with Garbanzo Beans</name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Bring 2 cups water to boil in medium saucepan. Remove from heat; add bulgur and salt and stir to blend. Cover and let stand until bulgur is just tender, about 20 minutes. Drain well, pressing to extract excess water. Transfer bulgur to large bowl; cool. Mix in remaining ingredients. Season with salt and pepper and serve.

*Also called cracked wheat; available at natural foods stores and supermarkets.

Makes 4 main-course servings.
</directions>
        <ingredients>Offer pita bread alongside.

2 cups water
1 cup bulgur*
1 teaspoon salt
1 15 1/2-ounce can garbanzo beans (chickpeas), rinsed, drained
1 cup diced plum tomatoes
1/2 cup crumbled feta cheese
1/2 cup chopped green onions
1/3 cup chopped fresh mint
1/3 cup chopped fresh Italian parsley
3 tablespoons fresh lemon juice
1 1/2 tablespoons olive oil
2 teaspoons grated lemon peel
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Butterflied Chicken with Thyme, Lemon and Garlic</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Cut out the back(spine) of the chicken and slice breast bone to flatten chicken, trim fat, rinse clean, and pat dry.

Add everything to a big Ziploc bag and marinate for a day or overnight.

Grill 5+minutes on direct head skin side down, lid open. Grill 5+ on other side, lid open. Move to indirect heat with lid closed until internal temp is 160-165f.

Cover with foil for at least 10 minutes, while vegetables are grilling.

Cut at all joints before serving.

</directions>
        <ingredients>1/2 cup canola oil
2 tablespoons
2 tablespoons
2 tablespoons grated lemon zest
1 tablespoon chopped onion
Pinch crushed red pepper flakes
1 (6-pound) whole chicken, butterflied
Salt and freshly ground black pepper
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Summer</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>California Grilled Vegetable Sandwich</name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Grill peppers until black. Place in bag to continue cooking.

Mix mayo, garlic, and lemon juice and refrigerate.
Slice zucchini, eggplant, and squash.
Slice buns or bread.

Remove blackened skins, core, and seeds. Cut in strips.

Oil, salt and pepper, and grill zucchini, squash, and eggplant.

Spread sauce on both halves of bread. Cover tops with feta cheese. Heat both halves in indirect grill heat after vegetables are done.

When cheese is starting to melt, layer on vegetables and serve.

</directions>
        <ingredients>1/2 cup mayonnaise
3 cloves garlic, minced
2 tablespoon lemon juice
1/8 cup olive oil
2 red bell peppers
2 yellow bell peppers
2 small zucchini
1 small eggplant, sliced
1 small yellow squash, sliced
focaccia bread pieces, split horizontally or
8 cibatta square buns
1/2 cup crumbled feta cheese</ingredients>
        <occasion>Summer</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Caramel Corn</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>Other</cuisine>
        <directions>Place the popped popcorn into two shallow greased baking pans. You may use roasting pans, jelly roll pans, or disposable roasting pans. Add the peanuts to the popped corn if using. Set aside.
Preheat the oven to 250 degrees F (120 degrees C). Combine the brown sugar, corn syrup, margarine and salt in a saucepan. Bring to a boil over medium heat, stirring enough to blend. Once the mixture begins to boil, boil for 5 minutes while stirring constantly.
Remove from the heat, and stir in the baking soda and vanilla. The mixture will be light and foamy. Immediately pour over the popcorn in the pans, and stir to coat. Don't worry too much at this point about getting all of the corn coated.
Bake for 1 hour, removing the pans, and giving them each a good stir every 15 minutes. Line the counter top with waxed paper. Dump the corn out onto the waxed paper and separate the pieces. Allow to cool completely, then store in airtight containers or resealable bags.
</directions>
        <ingredients>7 quarts plain popped popcorn
2 cups dry roasted peanuts (optional)
2 cups brown sugar
1/2 cup light corn syrup
1 teaspoon salt
1 cup margarine
1/2 teaspoon baking soda
1 teaspoon vanilla extract
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>12</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Carrot Macaroni and Cheese</name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>Other</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat oven to 350 degrees. In medium saucepan, combine carrots with zest and juice and ¼ cup water. Season with salt; bring to boil. Cover; simmer over moderate heat until carrots are very soft, about 30 minutes. Discard zest. Transfer carrots and any liquid to blender; purée until very smooth.

Meanwhile, in large saucepan of boiling salted water, cook pasta until al dente. Drain pasta, reserving 1 cup cooking water. Return pasta to pot. Add reserved water and carrot purée, cook over moderate heat, stirring frequently, until pasta is coated with thickened sauce, about 5 minutes. Stir in three-fourths of cheese and cook, stirring until very creamy, 2 to 3 minutes longer. Stir in tarragon; season with salt and white pepper. Transfer pasta to medium baking dish; top with remaining cheese. Bake until cheese is melted and lightly browned, about 20 minutes. Let stand for 5 minutes before serving.
</directions>
        <ingredients>3/4 lb carrots, peeled and thinly sliced
Zest and juice of 1 navel orange, zest removed in strips with vegetable peeler
Salt
3 cups penne rigate (9 oz)
3 oz sharp cheddar cheese, shredded (1½ cups)
1 tbsp chopped tarragon
Freshly ground white pepper
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Ceasar salad dressing</name>
        <category>Condiment</category>
        <cuisine>Other</cuisine>
        <directions>Lower egg into boiling water. Remove from heat immediately. Remove egg from waterand place in cold water.

Mix lemon juice, mustard, and garlic wisk in oil and add anchovies

Add egg and mix in well before serving.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 egg
3 Tablespoons Lemon juice
1 clove garlic minced
1 teas dijon mustard
1/3 cup olive oil
6 flat anchovies
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Cheese and basil stuffed pasta shells </name>
        <category>Pasta</category>
        <cuisine>Other</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat oven to 375. Cook pasta sheels according to package directions drain well. Meanwhile, brown beef in a medium saucepan, breaking up with a spoon to crumble. When meat is no longer pink drain excess fat and add sauce to pan. Simmer over low heat for 10 min. Spread 3/4 of the sauce in the bottom of a 13 by 9 inch baking pan. set aside in a medium bowl, stir together ricotta chesse, 1 1/2 cups mozzarella cheese, 1/4 cup parmessan cheese, egg, basil, garlic salt and pepper. Carefully spoon cheese into cooked shells and place i prepared pan. Drizzle remaining sauce over pasta and cover lightly with foil; bake for 30 min. Remove foil and sprinkle with remaining mozzarella and parmesan cheeses; bake for 15 min. more or until cheese is melted and pasta is hot a bubbly.
</directions>
        <ingredients>12 cooked jumbo pasta shells
1 lb. ground beef
1 (26 oz) jar pasta sauce or 2 cups. Hearty Marinara Sauce
1 15oz. container ricotta cheese
2 cups shredded mozarella cheese dived
1/2 cu. shredded parmesan cheese dived
1 egg
1 1/2 tsp. dried basil
1 tsp. garlic salt
1/4 tsp. pepper</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Cheese-Filo-wrapped Brie</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>1. Place nuts in a 9-inch pie pan and bake in a 350 regular or convection oven until golden, 5 to 7 minutes.

2. Meanwhile, chop tomatoes. In a small bowl, mix oil and butter.

3. Cut filo sheets into 12-inch squares. One at a time, brush squares lightly with butter mixture and stack.

4. Spread chopped tomatoes, basil, and toasted nuts in center of filo stack in a round that matches the size of the cheese. Place cheese on top of tomato mixture. Fold corners of filo stack, one at a time, over cheese and brush lightly with butter mixture. Press filo against cheese to make a smooth package.

5. Place wrapped cheese, smooth side up, in 9-inch pie pan. Brush top of filo with remaining butter mixture.

6. Bake in a 350 regular or convection oven until filo is golden, 25 to 30 minutes. Cool about 10 minutes.

7. With a wide spatula, transfer filo-wrapped brie to a plate. To serve, cut a big X in center or cut off a corner so guests can scoop out cheese mixture.
</directions>
        <ingredients>NOTES: Thaw frozen filo dough in the refrigerator for at least 8 hours. 
You can prepare cheese through step 5 up to 1 day ahead; cover and chill. Serve with thin baguette slices or crackers. 
MAKES: 8 servings
1/4 cup pine nuts
1/4 cup oil-packed dried tomatoes, drained, with 1 tablespoon oil reserved
2 tablespoons melted butter 
4 sheets (12 by 18 in.) filo dough, thawed if frozen (see notes)
1/4 cup chopped fresh basil leaves
1 round (8 oz.) firm-ripe brie cheese</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Cheesy Mediterranean Artichoke Pasta</name>
        <category>Pasta</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Toss hot pasta with remaining ingredients. Heat 5 minutes or until thoroughly heated. Serve immediately.</directions>
        <ingredients>8 oz penne pasta, cooked drained
1 can (14.5 oz) diced tomatoes, drained
1 can (14 oz) artichoke hearts, drained quartered
1 can (21/4 oz) sliced pitted ripe olives
1/4 c. EVOO
1/4 c. shredded parmesan or romano cheese
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chichen Soup</name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Stock
Put chicken in a stockpot. Add enough cold walter to cover. Bring just to a boil. Add a little more cold water to reduce to below boiling; stir once. Bring back just to a boil and reduce heat to very low so that liquid bubbles very gently. Skim off foam that collects on surface.

Add onions, carrots, bay leaves, parsley stems, peppercorns, and thyme. Adjust heat to keep surface just breaking with bubbles, but not boiling. Partially cover and cook, 2 to 3 hrs., skimming foam and fat occasionally.

Strain stock through a colander lined with several thicknesses of dampend cheesecloth, discard solids. If stock is not to be used immediately, cook to lukewarm. Refrigerate until fat rises to surface and congeals ( about 8 hrs). If stock will be used within 3 to 5 days, leave fat; skim fat when ready to use or if freezing stock.

Soup

In 8 qt. stockpot bring stock to a boil. Add carrots, celery, and onions; reduce heat to medium-low and simmer 10 min. or until veg. are tender.</directions>
        <ingredients>Chicken Stock

3 lbs. chicken
16 C. Water
2 med. onion,peeled and quarted
2 med. carrots, peeled and quarted
2 bay leaves
10 stems parsley
1/2 tsp. black peppercorn
1/2 tsp. dried thyme

Soup

16 C.Chicken stock
6 small carrots, diced
6 stalks celery, diced
3 onions, finely chopped</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken Braised in Red Wine</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>Middle East</cuisine>
        <directions>Place the bacon in a large, heavy pot and cook over low heat until fat is rendered and bacon is crisp. Remove bacon from pan and set aside.

Increase heat to medium-high. Sear chicken pieces in bacon fat until golden brown, 3-4 minutes per side. Remove chicken pieces and set aside.

Pour off fat, reserving 1 tablespoon in pan. Add carrots, onions and garlic and sauté until onions are soft and just beginning to brown, about 5 minutes. Sprinkle with flour, stir to distribute, and sauté for an additional minute. Deglaze pan with 2 tablespoons of wine, scraping up all the sucs, or brown bits, with a wooden spoon.

Return chicken and bacon to the pan. Add bay leaf and remaining red wine and bring to a boil. Reduce heat to low and simmer, covered, for 45 minutes to 1 hour, or until the sauce is mellow and thickened, and the carrots tender but not disintegrating. Check and adjust seasoning.

Serve with your favorite potato dish, or thick egg noodles. Sprinkle with minced parsley before serving.</directions>
        <ingredients>3 strips bacon, cut in 1/2-inch pieces
6 pieces skin-on, dark-meat chicken (mix of thighs and drumsticks)
Salt and freshly-ground black pepper
Large yellow onion, finely sliced
Large carrot, cut in 1/2-inch rounds
Garlic clove, minced
1 tablespoon flour
2 cups plus 2 tablespoons Charles Shaw merlot
Bay leaf
Parsley, leaves only, minced
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>2</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken Enchiladas</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>2 Tbl. salad oil
1/2 c. copped onion
2 c. chopped cooked chicken
1 can (7 oz) Ortega Green Chile Salsa
1 c. sour cream 
1/8 Tsp. salt
12 tortillas
1 c. light cream
1 c. chicken stock
1 1/2 c. cheddar/Jack Cheese</directions>
        <ingredients>2 Tbl. salad oil
1/2 c. copped onion
2 c. chopped cooked chicken
1 can (7 oz) Ortega Green Chile Salsa
1 c. sour cream 
1/8 Tsp. salt
12 tortillas
1 c. light cream
1 c. chicken stock
1 1/2 c. cheddar/Jack Cheese</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken Marbella</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In large bowl combine chicken quarters garlic, oregano, pepper, coarse salt to taste, vinegar, olive oil, prunes, olives, and capers and juice, bay leaves. Cover and let marinate, refrigerated, overnight. I

Preheat oven to 350 degrees Farenheit.

Arrange chicken in single layer in one or two large, shallow baking pans and spoon marinade over it evenly. Sprinkle chicken pieces with brown sugar and pour white wine around them. Bake for 50 minutes to 1 hour, basting frequently with pan juices. Chicken is done when thigh pieces, pricked with fork at their thickest, yield clear yellow (rather than pink) juice. With slotted spoon transfer chicken, prunes, olives, capers to serving platter. Moisten with several spoon-fuls of pan juices; sprinkle generously with parsley or cilantro. Pass remaining pan juices in sauceboat.
To serve Chicken Marbella cold, cool to room temperature in cooking juices before transferring to a serving platter. If chicken has been covered and refrigerated, allow it to return to room temperature before serving. Spoon some of reserved juices over chicken. Serves 10.</directions>
        <ingredients>4 2.5 lbs. chickens, quartered 
1 head of garlic, peeled and finely pureed 
1/4 cup dried oregano 
Coarse salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste 
1/2 cup red wine vinegar 
1/2 cup olive oil 
1 cup pitted prunes 
1/2 cup pitted Spanish green olives 
1/2 cup capers with a bit of juice 
6 bay leaves 
1 cup brown sugar 
1 cup white wine
1/2 cup Italian parsley or fresh cilantro, finely chopped
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken Marbella </name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In large bowl combine chicken quart;* garlic, oregano, pepper, coarse salt to I taste, vinegar, olive oil, prunes, olives. I capers and juice, bay leaves. Cover aJ let marinate, refrigerated, overnight.

Preheat oven to 350 degrees Fahrenr Arrange chicken in single layer in one or two large, shallow baking pans ai spoon marinade over it evenly. Sprink _, chicken pieces with brown sugar and I pour white wine around them. Bake : for 50 minutes to 1 hour, basting frequen with pan juices. Chicken is done when thigh pieces, pricked with fork at the thickest, yield clear yellow (rather than pink) juice. With slotted spoon transfer chicken, prunes, olives, capers to serving platter. Moisten with several spoonfuls of pan juices; sprinkle generousl with parsley or cilantro. Pass remaining juices in sauceboat.

To serve Chicken Marbella cold, cool to room temperature in cooking juices befor transferring to a serving platter. If chicker has been covered and refrigerated, allow it to return to room temperature before serving. Spoon some of reserved juices ove chicken. Serves 10.
</directions>
        <ingredients>4 chickens, 1.\ pounds each, quartered 1 head of garlic, peeled and finely pureed \ cup dried oregano Coarse salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste

1/2 cup red wine vinegar 
1/2 cup olive oil
1 cup pitted prunes
1/2 cup pitted Spanish green olives
1/2 cup capers with a bit of juice
6 bay leaves
1 cup brown sugar 
1 cup white wine
1/4 cup Italian parsley or fresh cilantro, finely chopped</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>10</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken Pasole</name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>Heat olive oil in a large saucepan over medium-high heat. Add oregano and next 4 ingredients (through onion and celery); saute' 2 minutes. Stir in tomatillos; cook 1 minute. Add broth and hominy; cover and bring to a boil. Uncover and cook 8 minutes or until heated. Remove from heat; stir in lime juice, salt and pepper. Divide evenly among 4 bowls. Top with avocado and radish. Garnish with cilantro, if desired.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 Tbsp. Olive Oil
1 Tsp. dried oregano
3/4 Tsp. ground cumin
1/2 Tsp. chili powder
2 garlic cloves, minced
1/2 C. chopped onion and celery
4 canned tomatillos, drained and coarsely chopped
2 (14 oz) cans fat-free-less sodium chicken broth
1 (15 oz) can white hominy, rinsed and drained
2 C. chopped skinless, boneless rotisserie chicken breast
1 Tbsp. fresh lime juice
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken Pot Pie</name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>Rinse frozen peas and carrots in cold water to separate;drain. Heat butter in 2 qt. saucepan over med. heat until melted. Stir in flour, onion, potato, liquid smoke, salt and pepper. Cook, stirring constantly, until mixture in bubbly, remove from heat. stir in broth and milk. Heat to boiling, stirring constantly. Boil and stir 1 min.. Stir in chicken and vegetables.

Heat oven to 425. Place filling in prepared pie shell. Bake about 35 min.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 pkg. (10 oz.) frozen peas and carrots
1/3 C butter
1/3 C flour
1/3 C onion
1 potato
dash liquid smoke
1/2 tsp. salt
1/4 tsp. pepper
1 3/4 C. chicken broth
2/3 C, Milk
2 1/2 to 3 C. chicken or turkey
Double pie crust
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken Strips</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Cut chicken into strips. Place in mayo, then bread crumbs. Place on a preheated stone and bake for 15 to 20 min. at 400-425.</directions>
        <ingredients>
Chicken Breast
Mayo.
Ritz Cracker Crumbs
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken Tikka Masala</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>1 Soak bamboo skewers in water.
2 Thread chicken on skewers, and marinate (in the refrigerator) for an hour or so.
3 Discard marinade.
4 For sauce, melt butter on medium heat.
5 Add garlic &amp; jalapeno; cook 1 minute.
6 Stir in coriander, cumin, paprika, garam masala &amp; salt.
7 Stir in tomato sauce.
8 Simmer 15 minutes.
9 Stir in cream; simmer to thicken- about 5 minutes.
10 Grill or broil chicken, turning occasionally, to cook through- about 8 minutes.
11 Remove chicken from skewers; add to sauce.
12 Simmer 5 minutes.
13 Garnish with cilantro Serve with basmati rice, naan or pita bread.

Note: You can make your own garam masala. McCormick also makes garam masala; it's available in super markets.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 ½ lbs boneless skinless chicken , cut in 1 inch cubes
Marinade
1 cup plain yogurt
2 tablespoons lemon juice
2 teaspoons ground cumin
2 teaspoons ground red pepper
2 teaspoons black pepper
1 teaspoon cinnamon
1 teaspoon salt
1 piece minced ginger (1-inchinch" long)
6 bamboo skewers (6-inchinch")
Sauce
1 tablespoon unsalted butter
2 garlic cloves , minced
1 jalapeno , minced
2 teaspoons ground coriander
1 teaspoon ground cumin
1 teaspoon paprika
1 teaspoon garam masala (buy in Indian market)
½ teaspoon salt
1 (8 ounce) can tomato sauce
1 cup whipping cream
¼ cup chopped fresh cilantro</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken Tortilla Soup</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>In a 5 to 6 quart nonstick pan over medium heat, stir onion, garlic, cumin, oregano, chili powder, and pepper until spices are fregrant, about 1 min. Add broth, tomatoes (including juice), and green chilies. over and bring to a boil over high heat.

Meanwhile stack tortillas and cut into 1/8 inch wide strips. Add to boiling broth. Reduce heat, cover, and simmer for 15 min. stirring occasionally.

Rinse chicken and broth and return to a boil over high heat. Reduce heat, cover and simmer until chicken is while in center (cut to test), about 5 minutes. Stir in clinatro and salt to taste. Lable into soup bowls, garnish with avocado, and add cheese to taste.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1/3 C. chopped onion
3 cloves garlic, peeled and chopped
3/4 tsp. ground cumin
3/4 tsp. dried oregano
1/4 tsp. chili powder
1/4 tsp. pepper
8 C. chicken broth
1 Can (14oz) diced tomatoes
1 can(4 oz) diced green chilies
10 corn torillas (6 inch wide)
1 1/2 lbs. boned, skinned chicken breasts
1 frim-ripe avocado 
2 Tbl. chopped fresh cilantro
salt
about 1/2 C. shredded cheddar cheese</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken Verde Stew with Hominy</name>
        <category>Appetizer</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>1. Preheat broiler to high.

2. Halve, stem, and seed chiles. Place chiles, skin side up, on a foil-lined baking sheet coated with cooking spray; broil for 5 minutes or until charred. Place chiles in a paper bag; seal. Let stand for 15 minutes. Peel and discard skins. Arrange tomatillos on prepared baking sheet, and broil 14 minutes or until blackened, turning once. Combine the chiles, tomatillos, 1/4 cup cilantro, cumin, and oregano in a blender. Add 1 cup broth; process until smooth.

3. Heat a large Dutch oven over medium-high heat. Add 2 teaspoons olive oil; swirl to coat. Add onion, carrot, celery, and bell pepper; sauté for 2 minutes, stirring occasionally. Stir in flour; sauté for 2 minutes, stirring frequently. Add garlic; sauté for 30 seconds, stirring constantly. Place onion mixture in a large bowl.

4. Sprinkle chicken with 1/2 teaspoon salt and 1/4 teaspoon black pepper. Add 2 teaspoons oil to pan; swirl to coat. Add half of chicken; sauté 3 minutes. Add browned chicken to onion mixture. Repeat procedure with remaining chicken and 2 teaspoons oil. Combine remaining 1 cup broth, tomatillo mixture, onion mixture, and hominy in pan over medium-high heat, and bring to a boil. Cover, reduce heat, and simmer for 45 minutes, stirring occasionally. Stir in 1/2 teaspoon salt and 1/4 teaspoon black pepper. Ladle 1 2/3 cups stew into each of 6 bowls, and top each with 1 tablespoon sour cream. Garnish with cilantro, if desired.
</directions>
        <ingredients>2 Anaheim chiles
Cooking spray
1 1/2 pounds tomatillos
1/4 cup finely chopped fresh cilantro
1 1/2 teaspoons ground cumin
1 teaspoon dried oregano
2 cups fat-free, lower-sodium chicken broth, divided
2 tablespoons olive oil, divided
1 1/2 cups finely chopped onion
1/2 cup chopped carrot
1/2 cup chopped celery
1/2 cup chopped red bell pepper
3 tablespoons all-purpose flour
4 teaspoons finely chopped garlic
1 pound skinless, boneless chicken thighs, cut into 1 1/2-inch pieces
3/4 teaspoon kosher salt, divided
1/2 teaspoon black pepper, divided
1 (29-ounce) can golden hominy, rinsed and drained
6 tablespoons reduced-fat sour cream
Cilantro leaves (optional)
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken and Bread Salad</name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>1. In a blender, whirl olive oil, lemon juice, feta, garlic, basil, oregano, salt, and pepper until smooth.

2. In a large bowl, combine chicken, bread cubes, tomatoes, red and yellow bell pepper, onion, and olives. Add dressing and mix gently to coat.

3. Divide salad mix evenly among four plates. Mound bread mixture over greens.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1/2 cup olive oil
1/4 cup lemon juice
1/3 cup crumbled feta cheese (about 3 oz.)
3 cloves garlic, peeled
2 tablespoons packed fresh basil leaves, rinsed
1/2 teaspoon dried oregano
1/2 teaspoon salt
1/4 teaspoon pepper
12 ounces cooked chicken, shredded or cut into 1-inch chunks
1 baguette (8 oz.), cut into 1-inch cubes
1 cup cherry tomatoes (about 8 oz.), rinsed, stemmed, and halved 
1/2 red bell pepper (about 4 oz.), rinsed, stemmed, seeded, and cut into 
1-inch chunks
1/2 yellow bell pepper (about 4 oz.), rinsed, stemmed, seeded, and cut 
into 1-inch chunks
1/3 cup thinly sliced red onion
1/4 cup chopped pitted calamata olives
4 ounces salad mix, rinsed and crisped
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken in White Garlic Sauce</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Place the chicken in a pan and cover with water. Add the bay leaf, onion, and salt and pepper. Bring to a boil, then reduce the heat and simmer for 20 to 30 minutes, or until tender but firm.

Remove the chicken pieces from the pan with a slotted spoon, pass the stock through a fine sieve, and skim off and discard as much fat as possible. Measure the stock; you should have about 3 cups. If it is more, reduce it over
high heat. If it is less, add a little water.

Heat some olive oil in a deep skillet. Lightly dredge the chicken with flour and fry until golden brown on all sides. Transfer the fried pieces to paper towels and keep warm.

Discard the frying oil from the skillet and wipe with paper towels. Heat 3 tablespoons of olive oil over low heat, and whisk in the 3 tablespoons of flour. Continue whisking for about 1 minute, until it begins to froth.

Remove from the heat and add the garlic, reserved stock, wine, vinegar, and walnuts, whisking constantly. Return to the stove and continue whisking over medium heat until the sauce begins to thicken. Taste and add more salt and
pepper if necessary.

Arrange the chicken on a heated plate, and pour the sauce over it. Sprinkle with almonds and serve immediately.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 free range (about 3 lbs.), cut into serving pieces Chicken
1 Bay Leaf
1 medium, quartered Onion
and pepper Salt
for dredging Flour
for frying Vegetable Oil
3 tablespoons Olive Oil
3 tablespoons Flour
4 -5 cloves Garlic
1/2 cup White Wine
2 tablespoons, red wine type Vinegar
1 cup, ground Walnuts
1/2 cup, coarsely crushed Almonds
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chicken soup with Dumplings</name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In a large bowl sift together flour, baking powder, and salt. In a small bowl combine eggs and milk. Make a well in center of flour; pour egg-milk mixture into well and stir until well combined. Set aside

In a stockpot , bring stock to a boil. Add carrots, celery, and oions; reduce heat to medium-low and simmer 10 min.

Drop dumpling batter into simmering broth, 1 tbl. at a time. Cover and simmer for 10 min. without lifting lid.

Serve at once.
</directions>
        <ingredients>See chicken soup recipe

Dumplings

2 cups cake flour
4 tsp. baking powder
1 tsp. salt
2 eggs, lightly beaten
3/4 cup milk

6 small carrots, diced
6 stalks cerery, diced
3 onions, finely chopped
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chile Verde Recipe</name>
        <category>Beef</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>Remove papery husks from tomatillos and rinse well.

Cut in half and place cut side down, along with 5 unpeeled garlic cloves, on a foil-lined baking sheet. Place under a broiler for about 5-7 minutes to lightly blacken the skin. Remove from oven, let cool enough to handle.

If adding you would like, you can add a couple Anaheim or poblano chilies. Either use canned green chiles or roast fresh chilies over a gas flame or under the broiler until blackened all around. Let cool in a brown bag, remove the skin, seeds, and stem.

Place tomatillos, skins included, into blender. Remove the now roasted garlic cloves from their skins, add them to the blender. Add chopped Jalapeño peppers, other chilies (if you are using them), and cilantro to the blender. Pulse until all ingredients are finely chopped and mixed.

Season the pork cubes generously with salt and pepper. Heat olive oil in a large, heavy-bottomed skillet over medium high heat and brown pork chunks well on all sides. Work in batches so that the pork is not crowded in the pan and has a better chance to brown well. Using a slotted spoon or tongs, lift pork out of pan and place in bowl or stock pan, set aside.

Pour off excess fat, anything beyond a tablespoon, and place the onions and the uncooked garlic in the same skillet and cook, stirring occasionally until limp, about 5 minutes. If your skillet is large enough to cook the entire batch of chile verde, with the sauce and meat, then add the pork back to the pan. If not, add the onion mixture and the pork to the meat in the stock pot.

Add the oregano to the pan. Add the tomatillo chile verde sauce to the pork and onions.

Add the chicken stock (enough to cover the meat). Add a pinch of ground cloves. Add a little salt and pepper. (Not too much as the chile verde will continue to cook down and concentrate a bit.)

Bring to a boil and reduce to a slight simmer. Cook for 2-3 hours uncovered or until the pork is fork tender. (Crock pot works well at this point too.)

Adjust the seasoning to taste with salt and pepper. Serve with Spanish rice and warmed flour or corn tortillas.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 1/2 pounds tomatillos
5 garlic cloves, not peeled
2 jalapenos, seeds and ribs removed, chopped
2 Anaheim or Poblano chiles (optional)
1 bunch cilantro leaves, cleaned and chopped
3 1/2 to 4 pounds pork shoulder (also called pork butt), trimmed of excess fat and cut into 1 to 2-inch cubes
Salt
Freshly ground black pepper
Olive oil
2 yellow onions
3 garlic cloves, peeled and finely chopped
2 Tbsp of chopped fresh oregano or 1 Tbsp of dried oregano
2 1/2 cups chicken stock
Pinch of ground cloves</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chili Con Carne</name>
        <category>Beef</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>Cook ground beef, onion, and garlic in 4 qt. saucepan, stirring occasionally, until beef is brown; drain. Stir in remaining ingredients except beean and tomatoes. Cook about 3 to 5 min. Add tomatoes, heat to boil, reduce heat, cover and simmer 1 hr, stirring occasionally.

Stir in beans. Heat to boil, reduce heat. Simmer uncovered about 20 min., stirring occasionally.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 lb. ground beef
1 large onion chopped (1 Cup)
2 cloves garlic, chopped
1 tablespoon chili power
1/2 tsp. salt
1 tsp. ground cumin
1 tsp. oregano
1/2 tsp. red pepper sauce
1 can (16 oz) whole tomatoes, undrained
1 can (15 1/2 oz) red kidney beans undrained
1 can (15 1/2 oz) black beans undrained
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chili Pepper Quesh</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat oven to 350.

Chop ham into cubes, set aside. Wisk eggs until light lemon-colored. Add flour and wisk until combined (flour may remain lumpy-that's okay). Add remaining ingredients. Pour into well-greased 9X13 casserole dish.

Bake 45 minutes until browned and knife inserted in center comes out clean. Let rest for 10 minutes.
</directions>
        <ingredients>10 eggs
1/2 cup flour
1/2 tsp. Salt (I omit the salt when using ham, otherwise it's too salty)
4 Tb. Butter, melted
1 pint low fat cottage cheese
1 tsp. Baking powder
16 oz. Monterey jack/chedder cheese, shredded
1 lb. Ham, thickly sliced
1 small can of Ortega chilis
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chinese Barbecued Pork w/garlic</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>Asian</cuisine>
        <directions>Make barbecued pork:

Preheat oven to 350F. and line a shallow baking pan with foil.

In a small bowl whisk together hoisin sauce, ketchup, soy sauce, garlic, and sugar. Put pork tenderloin in baking pan and coat with hoisin sauce mixture. Roast pork in middle of oven 35 to 40 minutes, or until a meat thermometer inserted in center registers 160F. Cool pork completely in baking pan.

Make garlic sauce while pork is cooling:
In a small bowl stir together sauce ingredients until sugar is dissolved.

Transfer pork to a cutting board and with a knife held at a 45 angle cut meat across grain into thin slices. Arrange pork, overlapping slices slightly, over noodles. Spoon garlic sauce over pork and sprinkle pork with coriander
</directions>
        <ingredients>For barbecued pork:
1 tablespoon hoisin sauce
1 tablespoon ketchup
1 tablespoon soy sauce
2 teaspoons minced garlic
1/2 teaspoon sugar
a 3/4-pound pork tenderloin

For garlic sauce
2 tablespoons soy sauce
1 1/2 tablespoons minced garlic
1 teaspoon rice vinegar
1 teaspoon sugar
1 teaspoon Asian chili oil, or 1 teaspoon Asian sesame oil plus Tabasco 
to taste

1/4 cup fresh coriander leaves, washed well, spun dry, and torn
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chinese Fried Rice Deluxe</name>
        <category>Grain</category>
        <cuisine>Asian</cuisine>
        <directions>Heat 2 tablespoons lard or cooking oil. Beat eggs with 1/2 teaspoon salt 
and scramble in oil until firm, breaking into small pieces. Remove and 
reserve. Heat remaining oil. Add scallion and shrimp and remaining salt. 
Cook until shrimp shows pink. Break up lumps of cold cooked rice. Add to 
shrimp. Stir until rice is heated and the grains of rice are separated. 
Make a hole in the center of the rice. Add all the rest of the 
ingredients except soy sauce. Stir until thoroughly heated and mixed. 
Sprinkle soy sauce over rice and mix evenly through. Salt and pepper to 
taste. Garnish with additional chopped scallions if desired.

Serves 4.
</directions>
        <ingredients>The secret of making fried rice lies in the use of cold, cooked rice. 
Freshly cooked rice will only produce a sticky mess.

6 tablespoons lard or cooking oil
2 eggs
1 teaspoon salt
2 scallions, chopped
1/2 cup fresh shrimp, shelled, deveined and diced
4 cups cold, cooked rice
1/2 cup cooked peas
1/4 cup canned diced bamboo shoots
1/4 cup diced boiled ham
1/2 cup diced cooked chicken
1/2 cup diced Chinese roast pork or left-over roast beef or veal
2 tablespoons soy sauce
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chipotle-Rubbed Shrimp Taco Salad</name>
        <category>Vegetable</category>
        <cuisine>Indian</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat oven to 350.

Combine first 5 ingredients in a small bowl, stirring with whisk. Gradually add oil, stirring constantly with a whisk.

Bake tortilla shells at 350 according to pkg. directions.

While shells bake, heat a grill pan over medium-high heat. Combine shrimp, chile powders, and salt in a large bowl; toss well to coat. Cover pan wit cooking spray. Add shrimp to pan; cook 2 minutes on each side or until done.

Combine lettuce, mango, tomato, and radishes. Drizzle vinaigrette over salad; toss to coat. Place about 1 1/2 cups salad in each tortilla shell; divide shrimp evenly among salads.
</directions>
        <ingredients>3 Tbsp. chopped fresh cilantro
3 Tbsp. minced shallots
3 Tbsp. fresh lime juice
2 Tsp. honey
1/8 Tsp. salt
2 Tbsp. olive oil
1 refrigerated (8") flour tortilla
taco salad shell kit (such as Azteca)
1 lb. peeled and deveined jumbo shrimp
1/2 Tsp. chili powder
1/4 Tsp. ground chipotle chile powder
1/8 Tsp. salt
Cooking Spray
6 C. pkg. romaine hearts
1 1/2 C. chopped peeled ripe mango (about 1 large)
1/2 C. cherry tomatoes, halved 4 radishes, quartered
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chocoflan</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>Put an oven rack in the middle of the oven and preheat to 350 degrees F.

Coat a Bundt pan with a little butter, then coat the bottom with 1/4 cup cajeta and put it in a large roasting pan. (The roasting pan will serve as a water bath during baking.)

For the cake: Add the butter and sugar to a bowl and using an electric hand mixer or stand mixer, beat until light and fluffy, then beat in the egg. Sift together the flour, baking powder, baking soda and cocoa in a medium bowl. Beat 1/3 of the flour mixture, and 1/2 of the buttermilk into the egg mixture. Repeat, ending with the flour mixture. Blend until well incorporated.

For the flan: In a blender, combine the evaporated milk, condensed milk, cream cheese, eggs and vanilla. Blend on high for 30 seconds.

Scoop the cake batter into the prepared Bundt pan and spreading evenly. Slowly pour the flan mixture over the cake batter. Cover with foil and add about 1-inch of hot water to the roasting pan.

Carefully slide the pan into the oven, and bake 1 hour, until the surface of the cake is firm to the touch, or an inserted toothpick comes out clean. When cake is done, remove from the water bath and cool completely to room temperature, about 1 hour.

Invert a large, rimmed serving platter over the Bundt pan, grasp tightly together, giggle a little and flip over. Remove the pan and scrape any remaining cajeta from the pan onto the cake, garnish with chopped pecans and serve!

Cook's Notes: The batters may appear to mix when you pour them into the pan, but they completely separate while baking, with the flan ending up on the bottom when it's inverted. I like eating it warm, but traditionally, it is chilled 24 hours before serving.

Flan is a rich, creamy, cooked egg custard. It is often flavored with vanilla and baked in a water bath to retain its delicacy.

Cajeta is a thick and creamy spread or paste made with caramelized sugar and milk. It is used as a desert on its own or as a topping. Also known as "dolce de leche," it is sold in many supermarkets, Latin specialty markets or online. It can be substituted with a thick caramel sauce
</directions>
        <ingredients>12-cup capacity Bundt pan
Softened butter, to coat pan
1/4 cup cajeta or caramel sauce
For the cake:
10 tablespoons butter, room temperature
1 cup sugar
1 egg, room temperature
1 3/4 cups all-purpose flour
3/4 teaspoon baking powder
3/4 teaspoon baking soda
1/3 cup cocoa powder
1 1/4 cups buttermilk
For the flan:
1 (12-ounce) can evaporated milk
1 (14-ounce) can sweetened condensed milk
4 ounces cream cheese, room temperature
3 eggs
1 tablespoon vanilla extract
For garnish:
1/4 cup cajeta or caramel sauce
1/4 cup chopped pecans
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>12</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Chocolate Banana Cake</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Cream sugar and margarine until fluffy and light. Stir in eggs, one at a time, mixing well. Sift flour, salt, soda, and add alternately with vanilla, buttermilk and sour cream.Stir in bananas. Mix thoroughly. Add nuts and chocloate and fold into batter. Pour into greased 9x13 inch pan or tube pan.

Bake at 350 for 45 min.
Frost if desired.
</directions>
        <ingredients>2 C. sugar
3/4 C. margarine
4 eggs
3 1/2 C. flour
1 Tsp. baking soda
1 Tsp. vanilla
1 C. buttermilk
2 Tsp. sour cream
4 big ripe bananas,(mashed)
1 C. chopped nuts
2 Hershey bars, grated or 3/4 pkg. miniature chocolate chips
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Cinnamon-Hazelnut Pancakes</name>
        <category>Breakfast</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>1. Toast hazelnuts in a 10 by 15 inch baking pan in a 350 regular or convection oven until golden beneath skins, 7 to 10 minutes. Pour onto a clean linen towel. When nuts are cool enough to handle, rub in towel to remove loose skins. Whirl hazelnuts in a food processor until finely chopped, or finely chop with a knife; you should have 1 1/4 cups. 
Reserve 1/4 cup to sprinkle over cooked pancakes.

2. In a bowl, mix all-purpose flour, whole-wheat flour, sugar, cinnamon, baking powder, baking soda, and salt. In a small bowl, whisk eggs, buttermilk, and butter until blended. Stir egg mixture into flour mixture until evenly moistened, then gently stir in remaining 1 cup hazelnuts.

3. Place a nonstick griddle or a 12-inch nonstick frying pan over medium heat. When hot, coat lightly with oil and adjust heat to maintain temperature (see The perfect pancake). Spoon batter in 1/3-cup portions onto griddle and cook until pancakes are browned on the bottom and edges begin to look dry, about 2 minutes; turn with a wide spatula and brown other sides, 1 1/2 to 2 minutes longer. Coat pan with 
more oil as necessary to cook remaining pancakes.

4. Serve pancakes as cooked or keep warm in a single layer on baking sheets in a 200 oven for up to 15 minutes. Sprinkle with reserved hazelnuts.
</directions>
        <ingredients>on baking sheets in a 200F oven for up to 15 minutes. 
1 1/4 cups hazelnuts (about 6 oz.)
1 3/4 cups all-purpose flour
3/4 cup whole-wheat flour
2 tablespoons sugar
2 teaspoons ground cinnamon
1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder
1/2 teaspoon baking soda
1/2 teaspoon salt
2 large eggs
3 cups buttermilk
3 tablespoons butter or margarine, melted
Salad oil
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Classic Crab Cakes</name>
        <category>Appetizer</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix the onion, celery and bell peppers. Season with salt and cayenne. Cook, stirring, until the vegetables are soft and slightly golden, about 5 minutes. Add the garlic and cook, stirring, for 2 minutes. Cool for 5 minutes. In a large mixing bowl, combine the crabmeat, green onions, cheese, parsley, mustard, mayonnaise, the cooled vegetables and 3/4 cups of the bread crumbs. Mix well. Divide the mixture into 10 equal portions and form them into 1-inch-thick cakes (patties). In a shallow bowl, combine the flour with 1 teaspoon of the Essence. In another bowl, whisk the egg 
with the water. In a third bowl, combine the remaining 3/4 cup bread crumbs and 1 teaspoon of the Creole seasoning. Heat the remaining 1 cup 
oil to 360 degrees F in a large saute pan over medium-high heat. Dredge the cakes first in the seasoned flour, tapping off any excess, then in the egg wash, letting the excess drip off. Dredge the cakes in the seasoned bread crumbs, coating them evenly. Gently lay the cakes, 3 to 4 
at a time, in the oil and fry until lightly golden, about 4 minutes on each side. Preheat the fryer. Fry the potatoes in batches until golden brown, about 3 to 4 minutes, stirring occasionally for overall browning. Drain the cakes on paper towels. Season the cakes with the remaining teaspoon Creole seasoning. Drain the potatoes on paper towels. Season 
with salt. Spoon the horseradish sauce in the center of each plate. Lay the crab cakes in the center of the sauce. Spoon the corn and tomato salad over each cake. Pile the potatoes on top of the salad. Garnish with parsley.
</directions>
        <ingredients>2 tablespoons unsalted butter 
1 cup finely chopped yellow onions 
1/2 cup finely chopped celery 
1/4 cup seeded and finely chopped red bell pepper 
1/4 cup seeded and finely chopped yellow bell pepper 
Salt 
Cayenne 
1 tablespoon chopped garlic 
1 pound lump crabmeat, picked over for shells and cartilage 
1/4 cup chopped green onions, green parts only 
1/4 cup grated Parmigiano-Reggiano cheese 
2 tablespoons finely chopped fresh parsley leaves 
1 tablespoon Creole mustard 
1/2 cup mayonnaise 
1 1/2 cups dried fine bread crumbs 
1 cup vegetable oil 
1/4 cup bleached all-purpose flour 
3 teaspoons Creole seasoning, (Essence) 
1 large egg 
1 tablespoon water 
2 large Idaho potatoes, peeled and cut into shoestrings 
1 recipe Fresh Horseradish Sauce 
1 recipe Roasted Corn and Tomato Salad

Melt the butter in a small saute pan over medium heat. Add</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Classic Herbed Salmon</name>
        <category>Fish</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat broiler. Combine oil, wine, and lemon juice in a resealable plastic bag. Add rosemary, thyme, oregano, salt, pepper and salmon. Marinate in refrigerator for 30 minutes.

Remove salmon from bad and discard remaining marinade. Boil salmon for 7 to 10 minutes, or until flakes easily. Turn once halfway through cooking time.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1/4 Cup olive oil
1/2 Cup White wine
1/4 Cup lemon juice
1/4 tsp. rosemary
1/4 tsp. thyme
1/2 tsp. oregano
1/4 tsp. salt
1/4 tsp. black pepper
1 lb. boneless skinless salmon filet

Tarragon Mayonnaise
1/2 Cup mayo.
1/2 tsp. tarragon
1/4 tsp. basil
1/4 tsp garlic powder

Combine mayo and spices in a small bowl. Cover and refrigerate for at least 30 min.
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Cold Fermented Pizza Dough</name>
        <category>Bread</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>1. Combine flour, salt, yeast, and sugar in the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with a dough hook attachment. Whisk to combine. Add water and knead on low speed just until mixture comes together and no dry flour remains. Allow to rest for 10 minutes. Knead on low speed for an additional ten minutes. The mixture should come together into a cohesive mass that barely sticks to the bottom of the bowl as it kneads. Depending on the type of flour used, you may need to add up to 1/2 cup additional flour. If dough sticks heavily to bottom of bowl, add flour 1 tablespoon at a time with mixer running until it forms a mass that just barely sticks to the bowl. Cover bowl tightly with plastic or transfer the dough to two gallon-sized zipper lock bags, seal, and refrigerate at least overnight, and up to 5 days.

2. Transfer the dough to a floured work surface and dust the top with additional flour. Using a bench scraper, divide the dough into six even pieces, approximately six ounces each. Using floured hands, shape each piece into a neat ball by gathering the dough towards the bottom. Coat four small containers with non-stick cooking spray or olive oil (large cereal bowls work great for this) and add one dough ball to each bowl. Lightly spray top of dough ball with non-stick cooking spray. Cover tightly with plastic wrap, and allow to rise at room temperature for 2 hours (dough should roughly double in volume).

3. Transfer 1 ball of dough to a medium bowl filled with flour and flip to coat. Lift it and gently pat off the excess flour. Transfer it to a floured surface and gently stretch it into a 10-inch circle, leaving the outer 1-inch edge slightly thicker than the center. The best way to do this it to start by gently stretching with your fingertips. Pick up the slightly stretched dough and place it on the opened face of your left hand. Toss it back and forth between your opened hands, rotating it slightly with each toss until it stretches out to around 8-inches in diameter. Return it to the work surface. With your left hand flat in the center of the round, use your right hand to stretch the edge of the dough out, rotating as needed until it is an even 10-inches in diameter.

Serves 4-6 people (makes six 10-inch pizzas).
</directions>
        <ingredients>20 ounces (4 cups) bread flour or all-purpose flour
.3 ounces (about 2 1/4 teaspoons) kosher salt, plus extra for assembly
.2 ounces (about 1 teaspoon) active dry yeast
.2 ounces (about 2 teaspoons) sugar
12 ounces water</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Cooked salsa</name>
        <category>Condiment</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>Saute onions and peppers in oil. Add to large pot with remaining ingredients. Cook until it looks right, adding more tomato products as needed. Can in sterile glass jars, leaving 1/2 inch headspace and wiping rims before sealing with clean lids and rings. Invert jars 5 minutes to sterilize lids. Cool at room temperature away from drafts.
</directions>
        <ingredients>10 cups onions -- chopped
5 cups bell peppers -- chopped 
20 cloves garlic -- chopped 
10 cups tomatoes
25 jalapeno -- chopped
1 7/8 cups white vinegar
2 tablespoons oregano
16 ounces tomato sauce
1 tablespoon cumin
1 tablespoon salt
fresh lime juice
cilantro
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Corn Bread</name>
        <category>Bread</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix and pour in loaf pan.

Bake at 325-350 until done
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 small sour cream
2 eggs
1 cdan creamed corn
1 can whole corn-use most of liquid
1 jiffy corn bread mix
chives</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Corn Dip with Crispy Tortilla Chile</name>
        <category>Condiment</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F. 
Melt 1 tablespoon of the butter in a large heavy skillet over medium-high heat. Add the corn, salt, and pepper. Cook, stirring occasionally, until the kernels turn deep golden brown, about 5 minutes. 
Transfer to a bowl. Melt the remaining tablespoon of butter in the skillet. Add the onions and bell peppers and cook, stirring often, until the onions are wilted, about 2 minutes. Add the green onions, jalapeno, and garlic and cook, stirring, for 2 minutes, or until the vegetables 
are softened. Transfer to the bowl with the corn. Add the mayonnaise, 1/2 of the monterey jack and half of the cheddar, and the cayenne and mix well. Pour into an 8-inch square baking dish and sprinkle the remaining cheese on top. Bake until bubbly and golden brown, 10 to 12 minutes. Serve hot with the chips.</directions>
        <ingredients>2 tablespoons unsalted butter
3 1/2 cups corn kernels (from 4 ears fresh white or yellow corn)
1/2 teaspoon salt
1/8 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper
1 cup finely chopped yellow onions
1/2 cup finely chopped red bell peppers
1/4 cup chopped green onions (green and white parts)
1 jalapeno, seeded and minced
2 teaspoons minced garlic
1/2 to 1 cup mayonnaise
4 ounces monterey jack or cheddar, shredded 
4 ounces sharp cheddar, shredded 
1/4 teaspoon cayenne
Tortilla chips, for dipping</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Crab Cakes (Oprah)</name>
        <category>Seafood</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Wisk egg-stir in lemon juice. worsh. sauce, and mayo. Add dry ingred. to adove, except parsley and crabmeat. To crabmeat add parsley and 2 Tbl. bread crumbs. Mix gently. Fold into wet mixture. Form into 4-3 inch cakes. Coat with bread crumbs. chile for 1 hr.

Place on greased cookie sheet. Bake 425 15-20 min. or until lightly brown on outside. Turn once half way thru cooking
time.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 Egg
2 tsp. lemon juice
1/4 tsp.worsh. sauce
2/3 C. mayo.
1/2 tsp. dry mustard
1/4 tsp. celery seed
2 tsp. old bay seasoning
1/4 tsp. salt
1/4 tsp. pepper
1 Tbl. parsley-chopped
2 Tbl. Bread Crumbs plus 1 1/2 C. for coating
1 lb. fresh jumbo crabmeat
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Cranberries Sauce</name>
        <category>Sauce</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Place 1st. three ingredients in sauce pan and bring to a rolling boil (about 8 min.) Remove from heat. Add jello stir until disolved. Refrigerate.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 lb. cranberries (washed, pick out bad ones)
1 1/2 C. white sugar
1 1/3 C. water
1 sm pkg. raspberry jello
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Thanksgiving</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Cranberry Pake (Pie+Cake)</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Cream together butter and sugar. Add eggs and beat well. Add flour and mix thoroughly. Dollop the mixture by spoonfuls over the cranberry layer and smooth the top with a spatula.

Place the pake on a baking sheet to catch drips while baking. Bake for 1 hour at 350 degrees or until the top is golden brown. Serve warm or at room temperature with ice cream.
</directions>
        <ingredients>Crust: Prepare your favorite pie crust to fit a 9-inch pie pan. Place in pan, flute edges, and leave unbaked.

Cranberry Layer:
2 cups fresh whole cranberries, rinsed and drained(use the whole package)
1/2 cup sugar
1/2 cup chopped pecans
Mix all ingredients and place in unbaked crust.

Cake Layer:
3/4 cup softened butter
1 cup sugar
2 eggs
1 cup flour</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Cream of Potato Soup</name>
        <category>Sauce</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Place ingredients in electric blender in order indicated. Cover container and turn on blender. Mix about 1 minute. Pour into saucepan or double boiler and heat thoroughly over moderate heat, stirring frequently. Serve immediately in soup cups, sprinkled with chives. For a richer soup, stir in 1/2 cup light cream.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 cup diced hot cooked potatoes
2 cups milk
1 tablespoon chopped onion
1 chicken bouillon cube
1/2 teaspoon salt
1/8 teaspoon pepper
2 sprigs parsley
1 teaspoon butter
Chopped chives
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Creamy Mushroom Pasta with Grilled London Broil</name>
        <category>Pasta</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Marinate London Broil or Sirloin tips on all the ingredients overnight. Grill on all sides until internal temperature is 135-140. Slice and serve with pasta.

Bring a large pot of salted water to a boil.

In a small covered pot, heat the stock and dried mushrooms together over medium heat until simmering. Remove from heat and allow them to rest for 10 minutes.

In a large, high-sided braising pot, heat the butter and olive oil over medium heat until foaming subsides. Add the cremini mushrooms and sauté, stirring often, until golden brown, 6 to 7 minutes. Add the shallot, garlic, and thyme, and season with salt and pepper. Reduce heat to low and cook, stirring frequently until the shallot is soft, 1 to 2 minutes. Remove the reconstituted dried mushrooms from the stock. Add the stock to the fresh mushrooms and shallots, and cook until almost absorbed, 1 minute. Turn off the heat, and cover the pot.

Cook the fettuccine until al dente, reserving 1/4 cup of cooking water before draining.

In a mini food processor, blend together the reconstituted dried mushrooms and the crème fraîche. Add the mixture to the fresh sautéed mushrooms, and stir to melt the crème fraîche into a sauce. Toss in the pasta, and add just enough pasta water for the mushrooms mixture to lightly coat the strands of pasta. Toss with Parmesan.
</directions>
        <ingredients>For Meat Marinade

4 large garlic cloves, minced
4 tablespoons balsamic vinegar
4 tablespoons fresh lemon juice
3 tablespoons Dijon mustard
1 1/2 tablespoons Worcestershire sauce
1 tablespoon soy sauce
1 teaspoon dried oregano, crumbled
1 teaspoon dried basil, crumbled
1 teaspoon dried thyme, crumbled
1/2 teaspoon dried hot red pepper flakes
2/3 cup olive oil

For Pasta

1/2 cup low-sodium organic chicken stock
1/4 ounce dried wild mushrooms
1 tablespoon unsalted butter
1 tablespoon olive oil
1 pound cremini mushrooms, cut into eighths
1 extra large shallot, minced
2 medium cloves garlic, chopped
2 teaspons fresh picked thyme leaves
Kosher salt
Freshly cracked black pepper
1 pound dry fettuccine
1/2 cup crème fraîche(Use Mexican crema found at Mexican butcher shop - fresh)
1/2 cup finely grated Parmesan
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Creamy Wild Rice and Turkey Soup</name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Heat oil in large saucepan over medium heat until hot. Cook and stir carrots, onions, celery and garlic until onions are soft. Add chicken broth, wild rice and turkey. Heat 10 minutes. Add whipping cream; cook over low heat until heated through. Add salt and pepper to taste</directions>
        <ingredients>2 cups chopped cooked turkey
1 tablespoon olive oil
1 cup finely chopped carrots
1 cup finely chopped onion
1/2 cup finely chopped celery
2 gloves garlic, minced
2 cans (14 1/2 oz each) chicken broth
2 cups cooked wild rice
1/2 cup whipping cream
salt and pepper to taste
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Creamy-Spinach Ravioli</name>
        <category>Pasta</category>
        <cuisine>Other</cuisine>
        <directions>Cook pasta as directed on package.

Meanwhile, place cream cheese spread in large skillet. Add milk; cook on medium heat 1 to 2 min. or until cream cheese is melted and mixture is well blended, stirring frequently. Add 1/4 c. of the parmesan cheese, the spinach, dill and lemon peel mix well.

Drain pasta. Add to cream cheese sauce, toss to coat. Serve topped with tomatoes and remaining 2 Tbsp. Sprinkle with parmesan cheese.
</directions>
        <ingredients>2 pkg. (9 oz) refrigerated cheese ravioli
1/2 c. (1/2 of 8 oz tub) philadelphia chive and onion chream cheese spread
1 c. milk
1/4 c. plus 2 tbsp. grated parmesan chsses, divided
4 c. baby spinach leaves
3 Tbsp. chopped chopped fresh dill
grated peel from 1 lemon
6 cherry tomatoes, quartered
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Creole croutons</name>
        <category>Condiment</category>
        <cuisine>Other</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat the oven to 375. Toss bread cubes with olive oil and Creole Seasoning. Place on a baking sheet and bake until golden brown, for about 4 min. Store in an airtight container at room temp. for 3 days.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 cup day-old bread cubes
2 tsp. olive oil
Creole seasoning
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Crispy and Sticky Chicken Thighs With Squashed New Potatoes and Tomatoes</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Put potatoes in large saucepan of salted boiling water and boil until cooked. While potatoes are cooking, preheat oven to 400 degrees. Cut each chicken thigh into three strips and place in a bowl. Rub the meat all over with olive oil and sprinkle with salt and pepper, then toss. Heat a large frying pan, big enough to hold all chicken pieces snugly in one layer, and put chicken into the pan, skin side down. If you don’t have a pan big enough, feel free to cook the chicken in two batches.

Toss and fry over high heat for 10 minutes or so, until almost cooked, then remove with a slotted spoon to an ovenproof pan or dish.

Prick tomatoes with a sharp knife. Place in a bowl, cover with boiling water, and leave for a minute or so. Drain and, when cool enough to handle, pinch off their skins. Their intense flavor will infuse the potatoes.

By now the potatoes will be cooked. Drain them in a colander, and then lightly crush them by pushing down on them with your thumb.

Finely mince the oregano. Add 4 tablespoons of extra-virgin olive oil, a good splash of red wine vinegar, and some pepper, and give everything another bash. Add to the chicken with the potatoes, the tomatoes, and the rest of the oregano leaves. Toss everything together carefully. Spread out in a single layer in an appropriately sized roasting pan, and bake for 40 minutes in the preheated oven until golden.</directions>
        <ingredients>2 lbs new potatoes, scrubbed
Sea salt and freshly ground pepper
12 boned chicken thighs, skin on, preferably free-range or organic
Olive oil
2 lbs cherry tomatoes, different shapes and colors if you can find them
A bunch of fresh oregano, leaves picked
Extra-virgin olive oil
Red wine vinegar
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Crockpot Chicken Taco Meat</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>1. Dissolve taco seasoning into chicken broth.
2. Place chicken breasts in crockpot and pour chicken broth over.
3. Cover and cook on low for 6-8 hours.
4. With two forks, shred the chicken meat into bite-size pieces.
5. To freeze, place shredded meat into freezer bags with the juices.
6. Press out all the air and seal.
</directions>
        <ingredients>3 tablespoons taco seasoning, I use recipe # 4292
1 cup chicken broth
1 lb boneless skinless chicken breasts</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Crunchy Salt Shrimp w/giner sauce</name>
        <category>Seafood</category>
        <cuisine>Asian</cuisine>
        <directions>Devein shrimp in shells by pushing a toothpick perpendicular to each shrimp through a jooint to the back shell and about 1/8 inch under the vein; pull up to lift out dark vein. If it breaks, repeat at another shell joint. If using shelled shrijmp, slit shrimp backs and pull out vein. Rinse shrimp, put in a bowl and add sake and cornstarch; stir to mix well.

In another small bowl, combine soy sauce, vinegar and ginger.

Pour about 1 inch oil into a 14 inch wok or deep, narrow 3 to 4 qt. pan over high heat. When oil reaches 375 add half the shrimp; stir often until they turn pink and shells are crisp, about 2 min. (about 1 min. for shelled shrimp) with a slotted spoon transfer shrijmp to towels to drain. Repeat to cook remaining shrimp.

Drain oil from wok; discard or save for other uses. Set wok over medium heat, add garlic and salt, and stir until shrimp are coated with garlic mixture and h ot 1/2 to 1 min.

Pour shrijmp onto a platter, sprinkle with basil and serve with ginger dipping sauce. Eat shells, if desired, or peel shrimp.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 lb. shrimp in shells
2 Tbl. sake or dry sherry
2 Tbl. cornstarch
2 Tbl. soy sauce
2 Tbl. rice vinegar
1 Tbl. minced fresh ginger
About 1 1/2 salad oil
1 Tbl. minced garlic
1 Tsp. kosher salt
1/4 C. sliverec fresh basil leaves</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Cumber Raitha (Sunetra)</name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>Indian</cuisine>
        <directions>Add cucumber to yogurt and water. Roll cumin seeds to powder and add to yogurt. Add coriander and spices.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 cumber, peeled and grated
1 1/2 cup plain yogurt
1/2 c. water
1/4 c. fresh coriander leaves, chopped
1/2 tsp. roasted cumin seed
1/2 tsp. salt
1/4 tsp. cumin
1/4 tsp. chili pepper
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Deep Dish pizza Dough</name>
        <category>Bread</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>Preheat oven to 170

In large bowl of electric mixer, combine 2 1/2 C. of the flour and salt. Stir to blend dry ingredients thoroughly. In a small bowl combine the hot water, yeast, honey and oil, stir to blend well.

Add water mixture to flour mixture. Mix to blend, then beat at medium speed until smooth and elastic (about 5 min). Stir in about 1/2 C. more flour to make a soft dough.

Turn dough out onto floured surface. Knead until dough is smooth and satiney (8 to 10 min.), adding just enough flour (up to 1/2 C.) to prevent dough from being sticky.

Turn dough into a greased bowl. Cover with plastic wrap and a towel, and let rise in a warm place until doubled in bulk (30 to 40 min). Punch dough down, cover with inverted bowl, and let rise 10 min. use as directed in recipe.
</directions>
        <ingredients>3 to 3 1/2 C. unbleached flour
1 pck. quick-rise active dry yeast
3/4 tsp. salt
1 1/4 C. hot (115-125F) water
2 tsp. honey
1 Tbl. olive oil</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Falafels</name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>Middle East</cuisine>
        <directions>Whizz bread in a food processor until you have chunky crumbs. Add chickpeas, onion, parsley, cumin and a little salt. Whizz again until you have a paste that is still a little chunky. Chunks of chickpeas is desired in paste.

Using a tablespoon and your hands form into rounds or little logs that are about the size of a "C" size battery.

Heat enough oil to just cover the falafels in a medium saucepan until 375 degrees. Add about 5 of the falafels and fry for 1-2 minutes or until deep brown. Do not allow them to touch the bottom of the pan during the first 10 seconds or they will stick and beak apart. If they oil is not hot enough the falafels will break apart. Remove and drain on paper towels. Keep warm while you repeat with the remaining batches, making sure the oil is hot enough between each.
</directions>
        <ingredients>2 round pita bread (75g / 3oz), torn
2 can chickpeas (400g / 14oz), drained
1 small red onion, peeled &amp; finely diced
1 small bunch flat leaf parsley, chopped
4 teaspoons ground cumin
peanut or other oil for frying
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Fava Puree</name>
        <category>Vegetable</category>
        <cuisine>Middle East</cuisine>
        <directions>Place beans in a bowl, cover with water and soak overnight. Drain and remove skins. Heat oil in a large saucepan, add onions and saute until softened, 5 to 7 minutes. Add the reserved beans, sugar, salt to taste, and water. Stir to blend, then cover pan and simmer for 45 minutes, or until beans are very soft. Add the lemon juice, simmer for 5 more minutes, and taste for seasoning. Puree bean mixture in a blender or food processor until smooth, then transfer to a bowl and chill until firm. To serve, either garnish the top with fresh dill, or invert puree onto a serving dish and garnish with the dill and lemon slices.</directions>
        <ingredients>2 cup Dried fava beans 
1/3 cup Extra-virgin olive oil 
1 lrg Onion, finely chopped 
1 tbl Sugar 
Salt, to taste 
3 cup Water 
Juice of 1/2 lemon 
Fresh dill, for garnish 
Lemon slices, for garnish</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Feta and Strawberry Salad</name>
        <category>Vegetable</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Toss all ingredients except dressing in large bowl. Add dressing just before serving; mix lightly.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 pkg. mixed baby greens
3/4 c. sliced fresh strawberries
1/2 c. crumbled feta cheese
3 Tbsp. sliced almonds, toasted
1/4 balsamic vinaigrette dressing</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Fettuccine Alfredo w/ Prosciutto </name>
        <category>Pasta</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>In a 5-6 qt. pan, combine broth, milk, and fettuccine (break fettuccine if necessary to fit into pan); cover and bring to a boil over high heat, stirring occasionally. Reduce heat to medium-high and cook, uncovered, stirring often to separate noodles, for 5 minutes. Add peas and stir occasionally until pasta is tender to bite, 2 to 4 min. longer.

Meanwhile, separate prosciutto slices and cut crosswise into 1/4 inch wide stripes.

In a small bowl, mix cornstarch with 2 tablespoons water until smooth. Add to pasta mixture and stir until it boils and thickens. Add sour cream, nutmeg, and salt and pepper to taste; stir until well blended and heated through, about 1 min. Stir in prosciutto. Spoon onto plates.</directions>
        <ingredients>3 1/2 C. fat-skimmed chicken broth
2 c. low-fat milk
3/4 lb. dried fettuccine
1 1/2 c. (10 oz) frozen petite peas
1 oz. thin-sliced prosciutto
1 /12 tsp. cornstarch
1 C. reduced fat sour cream
1/2 c. grated parmesan cheese
1/4 tsp. freshly grated netmeg or ground nutmeg
salt and pepper</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Fettucini Alfredo with Fresh Frozen Veggetables</name>
        <category>Pasta</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>1. Saute crushed garlic in olive oil.
2. Start large pot of water to boil for cooking noodles.
3. Cut vegetables into 2 1/2 inch strips, 1/3 inch thick.
4. Steam vegetables for a short period of time leaving them crisp.
5. Add grated cheese to sauteed garlic, stir well. Add cream; continue to stir over low heat. Add salt, pepper and parsley to taste.
6. While noodles are cooking, bring sauce to a near boil; add flour mixed with a small amount of water to sauce to thicken, continue stirring while sauce thickens.
7. Gently add vegetables to sauce, stir gently, lower heat.
8. When pasta is al dente, drain in colander.
9. Serve with alfredo sauce on top.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 lb. fettucini noodles
1 pt. light cream
3 oz. grated Parmesan, Romano cheese
2 cloves garlic
4 tbsp. olive oil
Salt &amp; pepper to taste
Parsley
Bag of fresh frozen mixed vegetables 
or
2 yellow squash
1 zucchini
1 bunch broccoli
2 carrots
3 tbsp. flour</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Fire Roasted Tomato Chipotle Salsa</name>
        <category>Condiment</category>
        <cuisine>Mexican</cuisine>
        <directions>Heat a tablespoon of olive oil in a saute pan over medium heat until lightly smoking. Add the onion, and saute until carmelized, about 10 minutes. Transfer the onion, half the blackened tomatoes and garlic to a food processor or blender, and pulse until finley chopped but not pureed. Add the cilantro and chipotle chiles and pulse again to mix.

Peel, seed and chop the remaining pound of tomatoes and fold in together with the remaining 1/4 cup olive oil, vingar, salt and sugar.
Variation: Substitute the tomatoes for tomatillos.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1/4 cup Virgin olive oil
1 Tablespoon Virgin olive oil
2 Pounds Roma tomatoes, -- blackened
1/2 onion -- peeled and chopped
4 teaspoons roasted garlic -- finely minced
1/2 cup cilantro leaves -- minced
4 whole chipotle chiles en adobo -- chopped
1/4 cup red wine vinegar
1 teaspoon sugar</ingredients>
        <occasion>Party</occasion>
        <serves>8</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Fish Tacos-Grilled</name>
        <category>Fish</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>Spray Pam on a foil made pan. Place fish on foil, sprinkle with cumin, garlic salt and lime juice. Grill for 10 min. or until fish is cooked. In a small bowl add chopped onion, garlic, salt, pepper, cilantro and lime juice stir to combine. Set aside. In another bowl add onion, garlic, salt, pepper, cilantro, lime juice and prepared salsa stir to combine. Set aside. Place chipolte chili and Adobo sauce in a food processor add sour cream and mayo. blend. Set aside. Heat tortillas. Add fish, coleslaw, and sauce to tortilla. Eat
</directions>
        <ingredients>Talapia
Cumin
Garlic Salt
Pepper
Salt
lime juice
Sour Cream
Mayo.
Chipolte Chili with Adobo sauce
Garlic
Onion
Cilantro
Tomato
Prepared Salsa
Coleslaw salad mix
Tortillas
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Party</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Flaming Cheese</name>
        <category>Appetizer</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Coat slices of Kassari in egg, then flour. Place in cast iron pan with oil. Bake at 350 for 10 min. (or until slightly melted). Remove from oven. Pour 1/4 C. brandy over cheese and light afire. Put out flames with lemon juice.

Place cheese slices over salad. Great side dish.</directions>
        <ingredients>Slices of Kassari Cheese
Olive Oil
Brandy
Egg
Flour
Lemon Wedges</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Flank Steak Pinwheels</name>
        <category>Beef</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Chop the tops of garlic bulbs, drizzle with olive oil, wrap with foil and grill until cloves are mushy. Cool and squeeze out cloves and mash.

Filet or butterfly flank steak. 
Season steak.
Smear with roasted garlic.
Spread mushrooms and cheeses.
Layer cured meat.
Roll and slice in 1.5 inch peices and secure with toothpicks.
Grill like steaks.
</directions>
        <ingredients>2 bulbs of garlic, roasted and mashed
Emerole's seasoning(any)
Bacon, prochuetto, or Italian cured bacon
1 cup earthy mushrooms finely chopped.
1 large flank steak
1/2 cup Grated Parmesan cheese
Soaked toothpicks.
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Flax Seed Wheat Bread </name>
        <category>Bread</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Combine the flours, salt, seeds, malt, and yeast in a bowl. Stir in the water and mix until thoroughly combined. This dough is not a terribly moist one: it should be slightly tacky but not sticky. When shaped into a ball it should easily hold its shape.

The seed and bran from the whole wheat prevent a high level of gluten development in this dough, so extensive kneading is not necessary.

Once all of the ingredients are thoroughly combined, place the ball of dough in a greased bowl. Cover with plastic wrap and leave to rise for an hour to an hour and a half.

Shape the dough into 1 large or two small loaves, cover the loaves with plastic, and give them another hour to rise. In the meantime, preheat the oven and baking stone to 425 degrees.

Brush the top of the loaves with water, score the loaves, and place them in the oven. Bake them at 425 for 20 minutes, rotate them 180 degrees, then bake them another 20 to 25 minutes. When done, they will be nicely browned on the outside, make a hollow sound when tapped upon, and register approximately 205 degrees in the center when measured with an instant read thermometer.</directions>
        <ingredients>7 oz bread flour
2 oz whole wheat flour
1 teaspoon salt
3.5 oz flax seeds
2 teaspoons malt powder
6 oz water
1 teaspoon instant yeast</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Fresh Garden Basil Cream Sauce</name>
        <category>Sauce</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In sauce pan over medium heat saute basil and onion in butter for 2-3 minutes. Add wine and simmer until liquid is reduced in half (approx. 10 minutes). Add broth and simmer additional 10 minutes. Add cream, basil, salt and pepper and simmer additional 10 minutes. Cool to thicken and serve at room temperature over fish.
</directions>
        <ingredients>2 tablespoons butter, melted
1 tablespoon chopped green onion
1/2 cup dry white wine
1-1/2 cups fish broth (or chicken broth)
1 cup heavy whipping cream
2 tablespoons fresh chopped basil
Salt and pepper to taste</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Fresh Horseradish Sacue</name>
        <category>Sauce</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In a saucepan, combine the horseradish, shallots, garlic, mustard and cream. Season with salt and pepper. Bring the liquid to a boil, whisking gently. Reduce the heat and simmer, stirring occasionally, until the sauce is thick enough to coat the back of a spoon, for about 12 minutes. 
Remove from the heat and keep warm.

Yield: about 2 cups
</directions>
        <ingredients>3/4 cup freshly grated horseradish or bottled, if not prepared with 
cream 
3 tablespoons minced shallots 
2 teaspoons minced garlic 
2 teaspoons Dijon mustard 
1 1/2 cups heavy cream 
Salt and white pepper</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Frozen Creamsicle Cake</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Line loaf pan with a double layer of plastic wrap, allowing a few inches of overhang along sides. Stir together cookie crumbs, zest, butter, and corn syrup in a small bowl, then press into bottom of loaf pan. Spread sorbet evenly over crumb crust and freeze 30 minutes to harden.

While sorbet is freezing, slightly soften frozen yogurt. Spread evenly over sorbet and freeze, covered with plastic wrap, until firm, at least 2 hours.

Using plastic wrap as an aid, lift frozen cake out of pan, then peel off plastic. Let stand 5 minutes to soften, then cut crosswise into 4 slices. Each serving contains about 197 calories and 3 grams fat.

Makes 4 servings.
</directions>
        <ingredients>Active time: 15 min Start to finish: 3 hr

16 low-fat vanilla wafers, finely ground in a food processor 
2 teaspoons finely grated fresh orange zest
2 teaspoons unsalted butter, melted and cooled
1 tablespoon light corn syrup
1 cup orange sorbet, slightly softened
1 cup nonfat vanilla frozen yogurt

Garnish: finely julienned fresh orange zest
Special equipment: a 3 1/2- by 7 1/2-inch (3 1/2-cup) loaf pan
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Garbanzo Bean Burgers</name>
        <category>Legume</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Using fork coarsely mash 3/4 c. garbanzo beans in med. bowl. Mix in onion and next 3 ingredients. Puree remaining garbonzo beans, egg white, tahini and garlic in processor until almost smooth. Stir into mashed garbanzo bean mixture. Season with salt and pepper. Shape mixture into four 1/2 inch thick patties.

Meanwhile, mix yogurt, hot pepper sauce and cumin in small bowl.

Place burgers in pita halves. Top with letuce, tomatoes and yogurt.

</directions>
        <ingredients>1 15-16 oz can garbanzo bean, rinsed and drained
3 tbl. minced red onion
3 tbl. chopped fresh dill
2 1/2 tbl. dry breadcrumbs
1 1/2 tbl.fresh lemon juice
1 large egg white
1 tbl. tahini
2 garlic cloves, peeled
1/3 c. plain nonfat yogurt
1/2 tsp. hot pepper sauce
1/4 tsp. group cumin

2 pita bread rounds, warmed, halved horizontally
2 c. shredded romaine lettuce</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Garbanzo Bean and Tuna/Salmon Salad</name>
        <category>Legume</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix lemon juice with onions while preparing other ingredients. Mix drained beans with drained tuna to onions. Add other ingredients. Adjust flavor with sea salt. Serve cold or at room temperature.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 cup of chopped red onions
The zest and juice of 1 lemon (can sub a tablespoon or two of cider vinegar)
2 five to six ounce cans of tuna packed in oil or flaked salmon.
2 15-ounce cans of garbanzo beans, rinsed and drained
1/2 cup of chopped parsley
1 or more teaspoon of Tabasco sauce
1/2 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper
Sea salt taste and olive oil if salmon is not packed in oil.
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Garlic Soup with Creole Croutons</name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Heat the oil in a soup pot over high heat. Add the onions, garlic cloves, bay leaves, salt and pepper. Stir well and saute until the onions are caramelized, for about 7 min. (don t let the onions get too dark; they should be sweet-tasting and a rich golden-brown color).

Stir in the stock, minced garlic, basil, and thyme, and bring to a boil. Reduce the heat and simmer for about 40 min. Turn the heat back up to high and whisk in the bread and the cream, and continue whisking until the bread has disintegrated into the soup, for about 10 min. Whisk in the Parmesan and remove from the heat.

While the soup is simmering, prepare the croutons.

Puree the soup in a food processor or blender.

Serve the soup hot, to with croutons.</directions>
        <ingredients>2 Tbl. olive oil
1 1/2 cups sliced onions
1/3 cup peeled garlic cloves (about 12 to 14)
3 bay leaves
salt to taste
7 turns freshly ground black pepper
2 qts. chicken stock or broth
1 Tbl. minced garlic
1 tsp. fresh chopped basil
1 tsp. fresh chopped thyme
2 cups diced day-old French or Italian bread
1/2 cup heavy cream
1/3 cup coarsely grated fresh Parmesan cheese
Creole Croutons</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Garlic and Oregano Marinated Chicken</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In a blender, combine the vinegar, lemon juice, lime juice, honey ancho chile powder, garlic and oregano and blend 30 seconds. With the motor running, slowly add the olive oil until emulsifies. Season to taste with salt and pepper. Makes about 3 cups.

Season the chicken quarters with salt and pepper to taste and marinate in the Garlic and Fresh Oregano Marinade 2 hours refrigerated.

Preheat a grill for 15 minutes.

Remove the chicken quarters from the marinade and shake off any excess. Grill until done, about 10 minutes on each side, and place on a serving platter, surrounded by the relish.

Serve the Garlic and Oregano Marinated Chicken on a platter surrounded by Grilled Pepper and Black Olive Relish
</directions>
        <ingredients>2 chickens, 2 1/2 pounds each, cut into quarters 
2 Tablespoons sherry vinegar (preferably Spanish) 
2 Tablespoons fresh lemon juice 
2 Tablespoons fresh lime juice 
2 Tablespoons honey 
1 Tablespoons ancho chile powder (available in Hispanic or specialty markets) 
12 garlic cloves, coarsely chopped 
1/4 cup fresh oregano leaves 
1 cups pure olive oil 
Salt and pepper
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Garlic-ginger roasted chicken</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Place your rinsed chicken in a ziplock bag and cover with marinade. Seal to exclude air so chicken is fully contacted by the marinade. Let marinate at least 8 hrs. or overnight for a more intense flavor.

When ready to roast, place breast side down in a shallow pan. Roast about 20-25 min. per pound at 350. Baste with the marinade or pan juices every 15 min. Turn the chicken breast side up during the last half hour. Chicken should be a nice mohogany color when done. Keep a close eye on it though; the marinade can scorch a little with all that honey in it.</directions>
        <ingredients>1/2 C. Soy Sauce
1/4 C. Honey
1/4 C. Vinegar
2 Tbsp. (+) chopped garlic
2 Tbsp. (+) minced ginger root

The proportions are a matter of taste.</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Ginger Steak w/ Sake-glazed Veggies</name>
        <category>Beef</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Combine first 6 ingredients in 13x9x2-inch glass baking dish. Add meat. Cover and refrigerate at least 2 hours and up to 1 day. Let stand at room temperature 1 hour before continuing.

Cook asparagus in large pot of boiling salted water until crisp-tender, about 4 minutes. Drain. Rinse under cold water to cool. Drain again.

Heat 2 tablespoons peanut oil in heavy large skillet over medium-high heat. Add red bell pepper strips and saute 3 minutes. Add crimini mushrooms and saute until mushrooms are soft, about 5 minutes. Add green onions and asparagus and saute until vegetables are tender, about 2 minutes longer. Transfer vegetables to serving platter. Tent with foil to keep warm.

Heat remaining 1 tablespoon peanut oil in same skillet over high heat. Remove steak from marinade; reserve marinade. Add steak to skillet and cook to desired doneness, about 4 minutes per side for medium-rare. Transfer to cutting board. Tent with foil and let stand 5 minutes.

Meanwhile, place reserved marinade in small saucepan. Whisk in cornstarch. Whisk over high heat until sauce thickens and boils, about 3 minutes. Remove sauce from heat. Season sauce to taste with salt and pepper.

Cut steak across grain on diagonal into 1/2-inch-thick slices. Arrange steak slices atop vegetables on platter. Spoon some of sauce over meat and vegetables. Serve, passing remaining sauce separately</directions>
        <ingredients>A soy-sake marinade is the base for a delicious reduction sauce. For convenience, begin this one day ahead and refrigerate the steak in its marinade overnight. What to drink: A fruity Zinfandel.

1/2 cup soy sauce
1/2 cup sake
1/4 cup (packed) dark brown sugar
3 tablespoons minced peeled fresh ginger
1 tablespoon balsamic vinegar
4 garlic cloves, crushed
1 2-pound flank steak

1 pound asparagus, trimmed, cut into 1 1/2-inch lengths

3 tablespoons peanut oil
2 red bell peppers, cut into 1-inch-wide strips
1 1/2 pounds crimini mushrooms, halved, each half cut crosswise into 
1/4-inch-thick slices
4 green onions, cut into 1-inch lengths

2 teaspoons cornstarch</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Glazed Apples</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Bring water and 1/2 cup sugar to a boil in a 3-quart saucepan, stirring until sugar is dissolved, then reduce heat and simmer 5 minutes. Add apples and simmer, stirring occasionally, until just tender, about 15 minutes. Transfer apples with a slotted spoon to a rack set over a baking pan, reserving poaching syrup, and drain apples 10 minutes.

Preheat broiler.

Arrange apple wedges in 1 layer in a flameproof shallow baking pan and sprinkle with remaining tablespoon sugar. Broil about 6 inches from heat, rotating pan occasionally and basting twice with poaching syrup, until apples are lightly browned on edges, 3 to 5 minutes.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 cup water
1/2 cup plus 1 tablespoon sugar
2 lb Golden Delicious apples, peeled and each cut into 8 wedges
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>9</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Grandma Comeau's Stuffing</name>
        <category>Other</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Combine ingredients. Cook until heated through.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 loaf (1 lbs) white bread
6 C.Hot chicken broth
1 lb. Hamburger Browned
1 onion-cooked until soft
3 C. celery
1/4 tsp. cloves
1 tsp. cinnamon
salt
pepper
garlic
3 eggs (?)
3 1/4 tsp. poultry seasoning
sage
marjoram</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Grape, Almond and Radicchio Salad with Black Olives</name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Place the radicchio and endive in a large bowl and add the black olives, grapes and almonds. Dress the salad with the balsamic vinegar and olive oil and season with salt and pepper. Toss to coat and serve immediately.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 head radicchio, cut into bite-size pieces(bitter, consider alternative)
1 head Belgian endive, cut into bite-size pieces  
1/2 cup black olives, thinly sliced
1/2 cup green grapes, cut in half  
1/2 cup whole almonds, toasted and lightly chopped
2 tablespoons white balsamic vinegar  
1/4 cup olive oil
Fine sea salt and freshly ground black pepper</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Greek-style Penne with Fresh Tomatoes</name>
        <category>Pasta</category>
        <cuisine>Greek</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix first 6 ingredients in large bowl. Set tomato mixture aside.

Cook pasta in large pot of boiling salted water until just tender but still firm to bite, stirring occasionally. Drain. Add hot pasta to tomato mixture and toss to coat. Season to taste with salt and pepper and serve.</directions>
        <ingredients>2 pounds tomatoes, halved, seeded, chopped
1 cup chopped green onions (white and pale green parts only)
7 ounces feta cheese, crumbled
6 tablespoons chopped fresh parsley
1/4 cup chopped fresh dill
1/4 cup extra-virgin olive oil

12 ounces penne pasta</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Green Bean-Tomato Salad with Herb Dress</name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>Greek</cuisine>
        <directions>Cook beans in large pot of boiling salted water until crisp-tender, about 3 minutes. Drain. Transfer to bowl of ice water and cool. Drain well. Place in large bowl.

Mix next 5 ingredients in small bowl; stir into beans. Season with salt and pepper. Garnish with parsley and cherry tomatoes.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1 1/2 pounds slender green beans, trimmed, cut into 2-inch pieces

3/4 cup chopped seeded tomatoes
1/3 cup extra-virgin olive oil
2 tablespoons balsamic vinegar
2 garlic cloves, minced
1 teaspoon dried oregano
1/4 cup chopped fresh Italian parsley
1 cup halved cherry tomatoes</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>8</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Green Chile Chili</name>
        <category>Salad</category>
        <cuisine>Greek</cuisine>
        <directions>1. Heat a large Dutch oven over medium-high heat. Add oil to pan; swirl to coat. Add beef; sauté for 5 minutes or until no longer pink, stirring to crumble. Add chopped onion, chili powder, and paprika; sauté 4 minutes, stirring occasionally. Add garlic; sauté for 1 minute, stirring constantly.

2. Stir in beer; bring to a boil. Cook 15 minutes or until liquid almost evaporates. Add salsa and the next 3 ingredients (through beans); bring to a boil. Reduce heat, and simmer for 30 minutes, stirring occasionally. Ladle 1 1/4 cups chili into each of 4 bowls, and top each serving with 1 tablespoon cheese. Sprinkle with green onion.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 tablespoon canola oil
12 ounces ground sirloin
1 1/2 cups chopped onion
1 tablespoon chili powder
1 teaspoon hot paprika
5 garlic cloves, minced
1 (12-ounce) bottle dark beer
1/2 cup salsa verde
1 (4-ounce) can diced green chiles, undrained
1 (15-ounce) can no-salt-added tomatoes, undrained and crushed
1 (15-ounce) can organic kidney beans, rinsed and drained
1/4 cup (1 ounce) shredded sharp cheddar cheese
1 green onion, sliced
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>8</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Green Chili Stew</name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>Italian</cuisine>
        <directions>Season meat liberally with salt and pepper. Line platter with paper towels. Heat oil or lard in large Dutch oven over medium heat until oil shimmers. Working in batches, brown meat lightly on all sides (it will not be cooked through), then transfer to lined platter. Add onion to pot, still over medium heat. Cook, stirring occasionally, for 4 or 5 minutes, until lightly browned. Add garlic, cumin, tomatoes, carrots, green chili peppers, then sprinkle flour over mixture; stir to coat evenly. Season lightly with salt, return browned meat to pot, stir to mix well. Cover mixture with water or broth; increase heat to medium-high, bring to boil, then reduce heat to low. Cover, cook for 1 hour, stirring occasionally. Taste and adjust salt or amount of green chili peppers as necessary. Broth should be well seasoned and fairly spicy.

Add potatoes; cook uncovered for 30 minutes or until potatoes are soft and meat is tender. Skim any fat from surface of broth. Let stew rest for 1 hour or more before serving. Or transfer to airtight container, cover, refrigerate overnight. To serve, reheat stew just until meat is warmed through. Ladle into warmed bowls; sprinkle with chopped cilantro.
</directions>
        <ingredients>Fresh green chili peppers, such as New Mexico or Anaheim, should be roasted over open flame on barbecue grill or gas burner, or under broiler. Once they are blackened and cooled, don food-safe gloves to rub off skins, remove stems and seeds, and coarsely chop peppers. Six large fresh chili peppers will yield about ½ cup chopped. A pretty fair approximation can be made with a combination of roasted fresh poblano chili peppers (sometimes called pasillas) and roasted jalapeños.

To toast cumin seeds: Place small skillet over medium heat. Add seeds and toast, shaking pan occasionally, for 2 to 4 minutes, until fragrant. Transfer to heat-proof bowl and cool completely.
2½ lbs well-marbled boneless pork butt 
(shoulder), cut into 2-inch cubes
Salt
Freshly ground black pepper
1 tbsp vegetable oil or lard
1 large onion, cut into small dice (about 2 cups)
2 to 3 medium cloves garlic, coarsely 
chopped
1 tsp cumin seeds, toasted and finely ground
¼ cup chopped tomatoes (may use fresh or 
canned)
3 large carrots, peeled, trimmed, and 
cut crosswise into chunks
½ cup chopped, roasted green chili 
peppers, or more to taste
1 tbsp flour
4 cups water or low-sodium chicken broth
1½ lbs russet potatoes, peeled and 
cut into large dice (about 2 large 
potatoes)
Chopped cilantro leaves, for garnish
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>5</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Grilled Chicked Cajun Sandwiches</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Roast peppers black until skins blister, cool in plastic bag, seed, peel and julienne.
Melt butter, remove all milk fat.

Cut chicken breasts to fit buns. Flatten with mallet to less than 1/2 inch. Season and grill. Baste with clarified butter on each turn. While chicken is grilling, butter buns with clarified butter and grill. Before chicken is done, mound sliced peppers and cover with cheese. When the cheese is melted move immediately to grilled buns. Keep sandwiches in closed grill(heat off) until ready to serve.
</directions>
        <ingredients>Skinned, boned chicken breasts
Cajun seasoning
Clarified butter from two sticks of butter
Pepper Jack cheese
2 medium sized red peppers
6 large buns</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Grilled Chicken Cacciatore with Garlic Mashed Potatoes</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Add chicken, Worcestershire, and balsamic vinegar to zip-loc bag and marinate for an hour or more.
Remove chicken and grill for 7-8 minutes turning frequently to sear and brown. Center should still be raw do not over cook.

Saute red peppers and onions in olive oil. When onions are soft and translucent add mushrooms and continue to cook for serveral minutes. Remove from pan. Place grilled chicken in pan and cover with sauted vegetables, diced tomatoes, wine, oregano, 2 cloves of chopped garlic, and some parsley. There should be plenty of liquid in the bottom of the pan. Season with salt and pepper and simmer for 20-30 minutes.

Peel and quarter potatoes. Boil in salted water.
Saute 4 cloves of chopped garlic in 1 tablespoon of olive oil and 2 tablespoons of butter. Well before they start to brown add chopped scallions. Stir to soften and remove from pan before any browning. 
Add cooked potatoes, garlic and scallions, ricotta cheese, milk, and shredded cheese to stand mixer. Mix and season with salt and pepper.

Sprinkle chicken with chopped parsley and serve from pan.</directions>
        <ingredients>4 chicken breast halves and 6 thighs skin removed and fat trimmed
12 oz mushroom caps (sliced thick)
12 oz red bell peppers (sliced thin)
1 medium red onion (sliced thin)
5 large starchy potatoes, such as Idaho
Extra-virgin olive oil
2 tablespoons butter
6 cloves garlic, chopped, divided
4 scallions, chopped
2 teaspoons fresh oregano
1/2 cup white wine
3 tablespoons balsamic vinegar
2 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce
1 (28-ounce) can fire roasted diced tomatoes, lightly drained (recommended: Muir Glenn brand)
Handful flat-leaf parsley, chopped
1 cup ricotta cheese
1/2 cup milk
1 cup shredded or grated Parmigiano-Reggiano or Romano</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Grilled Lemon Garlic Red Potatoes</name>
        <category>Other</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Grill Preparation:
Brush cool grates with oil to prevent sticking
Far Right Grill Burner: low
Far Left Grill Burner: medium (to maintain ideal temperature inside grill)
Preheat grill 5-10 minutes

Cut potatoes into quarters, brush with olive oil and place over low grill for 5 minutes per side. Remove and place on an 18 x 18 square piece of heavy aluminum foil. Combine garlic, butter, parsley and lemon pepper; drizzle over potatoes. Seal edges of foil tightly and place over low grill for additional 25 minutes or until soft and tender, stir occasionally. Open foil and drizzle with lemon juice. Serve hot.
</directions>
        <ingredients>1-1/2 pounds medium red potatoes
1 tablespoon olive oil
2 garlic cloves, crushed
1/4 cup salted butter, melted
2 tablespoons fresh chopped parsley
2 teaspoons lemon pepper seasoning
2 tablespoons fresh squeezed lemon juice</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Grilled Pepper and Black Olive Relish</name>
        <category>Condiment</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Combine the peppers, olives, garlic, thyme, parsley, and vinegar, and honey in a mixing bowl. Season to taste with salt and pepper. May be refrigerated up to 1 day. Use at room temperature.</directions>
        <ingredients>2 grilled red bell peppers, peeled, seeded and diced 
2 grilled yellow bell peppers, peeled, seeded and diced
1/2 cup pitted and coarsely chopped nicoise olives 
1 Tablespoons minced garlic 
1 Tablespoon fresh thyme leaves 
1/4 coarsely chopped parsley 
1/4 cup sherry vinegar (preferably Spanish) 
2 tablespoons honey 
salt and pepper
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Grilled Pork Chops with Anise-seed Rub and Mango Mojo</name>
        <category>Pork</category>
        <cuisine>Cuban</cuisine>
        <directions>Make mojo:
Puree mango, lime juice, garlic, jalapeno, and salt in a blender, then stir in cilantro.

Make rub:
Finely grind anise seeds and peppercorns in an electric coffee/spice grinder with salt and sugar. Transfer mixture to a small bowl and stir in oil.

Grill pork:
Brush both sides of pork with spice rub.

Grill pork on an oiled rack set 5 to 6 inches over glowing coals 2 minutes on each side. Move pork off to side of grill (not directly over coals; moderately low heat for gas grills) and cook pork, covered, turning once, until just cooked through, about 3 minutes more on each side.

Transfer to a platter and let stand, loosely covered, 5 minutes.

Serve pork with mojo</directions>
        <ingredients>For mango mojo
1 mango, peeled and coarsely chopped
1/4 cup fresh lime juice
1 large garlic clove
1 tablespoon chopped fresh jalapeno (including seeds)
1 teaspoon salt, or to taste
2 tablespoons finely chopped fresh cilantro

For anise-seed rub
1 tablespoon anise seeds
3/4 teaspoon black peppercorns
1 1/2 teaspoons salt
1 1/2 teaspoons sugar
3 tablespoons olive oil

4 (3/4-inch-thick) loin pork chops, trimmed</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Grilled Salmon with Fresh Basil Cream Sauce</name>
        <category>Fish</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Place salmon filets in re-sealable plastic bag. Combine all ingredients except salmon in food processor. Pour marinade over salmon and refrigerate 2 to 24 hours.
Grill Preparation:
Brush cool grill grates with oil to prevent sticking
Fill smoker box with hickory chips (previously soaked in water and drained), if desired
Smoker: low (preheat on high until hot and then reduce temperature)
Grill Burner: medium
Preheat grill 5 minutes

Place salmon on grill, skin side up for 3-4 minutes with closed lid. Turn over, place upright (skin side down) on sheet of aluminum foil over grill and continue cooking for 11-14 minutes with closed lid. Serve hot with fresh lemon wedges and basil cream sauce.</directions>
        <ingredients>4 (6 ounce) salmon filets with skin on bottom
1/4 cup fresh squeezed orange juice
1/4 cup soy sauce
1/2 cup rum, optional
3 tablespoons brown sugar
2 teaspoons finely minced onion
1 clove garlic, crushed
1 teaspoon catsup
1/4 teaspoon coriander spice
1/4 teaspoon dried red pepper flakes</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Grilled Swordfish with Rosemary</name>
        <category>Fish</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Stir wine, garlic, and 1 teaspoon rosemary together in an 8 inch square baking dish. Sprinkle fish with salt and pepper. Place in the baking dish, turning to coat. Cover, and refrigerate for at least 1 hour.

In a small bowl, stir together the lemon juice, olive oil, and remaining rosemary. Set aside.

Preheat grill for medium heat.

Transfer fish to a paper towel-lined dish, and discard marinade. Lightly oil grill grate to prevent sticking. Grill fish 10 minutes, turning once, or until fish can be easily flaked with a fork. Remove fish to a serving plate. Spoon lemon sauce over the fish, and top each fillet with a slice of lemon for garnish.</directions>
        <ingredients>1/2 cup white wine
5 cloves garlic, minced
2 teaspoons chopped fresh rosemary
4 (4 ounce) swordfish steaks
1/4 teaspoon salt
1/4 teaspoon ground black pepper
2 tablespoons lemon juice
1 tablespoon extra virgin olive oil
4 slices lemon, for garnish</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Grilled Tri-Tip with Savory Dry Rub</name>
        <category>Condiment</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>In a small bowl, combine all The ingredients for the rub. Mix until well blended. Place the roast on a cutting board, brush it with the olive oil, and rub the entire surface of the meat with the spice mixture. Wrap in plastic and refrigerate for at least 1 hour or up to 24 hours

Prepare a medium-hot fire in a charcoal grill, or preheat a gas grill to medium-high. Place the roast on the center of the grill, cover the grill, and cook, turning once after 15 minutes, for a total of 30 minutes for medium rare. Remove from the grill and allow to rest 15 minutes before carving.</directions>
        <ingredients>2 Tablespoons Minced Garlic
2 Tablespoons Minced Fresh Rosemary
2 Tablespoons Gound Coriander
1 Tablespoon Sweet Hungarian Paprika
1 Tablespoon Celery Seed
1 Tablespoon Ground Mustard
1 Tablespoon Cracked Pepper
1 Tablespoon Kosher Salt

3-Pound Tri-Tip Roast
2 Tablespoons Olive Oil</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Ground beef kababs</name>
        <category>Beef</category>
        <cuisine>Greek</cuisine>
        <directions>Note: Spice made from red peppers , crushed into oiled flakes or finely ground. Different types range from mild and sweet to very hot. Substitute mixture of sweet paprika and cayenne pepper.

In a small bowl, combine the sliced onions and sumac and toss well. Set aside until ready to serve. In a large bowl, combine the lamb, chopped onions, parsley, garlic, and kirmizi biber, and mix thoroughly, kneading with your hand. Add the egg white and salt, and knead mixture to a paste.

Divide it into 4 equal portions, and roll each portion into a flat, sausage shape. Wipe kebab skewers with oil, and using a dampened hand gently squeeze meat against the skewer. Secure meat onto skewer by squeezing mixture up and down, spreading it evenly and making sure it is firmly attached to the skewer. Preheat a grill to medium-high heat and brush it with oil. Roast the poblano chiles over the grill. Keep turning so the skin is evenly charred, without burning and drying out the flesh. Transfer charred peppers to a plastic bag, tie the top closed and let steam until cool to the touch, about 15 minutes. Peel off the charred skin by hand. Cut away stems, seeds and veins, and halve them. Heat the flat bread or pita until warm but not crisp, cut into cubes and wrap in foil to keep warm.

Grill the kebabs, brushing them with the melted butter, about 2 to 3 minutes per side. Grill the tomato halves at the same time. To serve, place the bread cubes on a serving platter or individual plates, drizzle with melted butter, remove meat from skewers and place over bread. Top with roasted peppers and tomatoes, drizzle with more butter, and serve immediately with the sumac relish.
</directions>
        <ingredients>2 x Onions, very thinly sliced 
2 tbl Sumac 
2 lb Ground lamb 
2 Onions, finely chopped 
1/2 cup Finely-chopped parsley 
4 Garlic cloves, minced 
1 tsp Kirmizi biber, see * Note 
1 Egg white 
Salt 
4 Poblano chiles -, (to 6) 
Flat bread or pitas 
Melted butter 
4 Tomatoes - (to 6), halved</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Halibut Cocktail</name>
        <category>Fish</category>
        <cuisine>Greek</cuisine>
        <directions>Chill halibut for several hours. Combine remaining ingredients, except lettuce, to make sauce. Chill. Arrange fish on lettuce in chilled cocktail glasses. Top with sauce. Serve very cold.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 1/2 c Cooked halibut; flaked
1/2 c Chili sauce
1 tb Prepared white horseradish
1 tb Fresh lemon juice
1 ts Salt
1/8 ts Pepper
4 Lettuce leaves; shredded</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Halibut Skewers [barbecue or broil]</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>Greek</cuisine>
        <directions>Whisk together Dijon-style mustard, melted butter, honey and lemon juice.
Season halibut steaks with salt and pepper.
Brush both sides of halibut steaks with honey-mustard mixture.
Cut halibut steaks into 1-inch [2.5-cm] chunks; thread onto skewers, alternately with an assortment of cut vegetables.
Barbecue or broil, until done.</directions>
        <ingredients>1/4 cup [60 mL] Dijon-style mustard
1/4 cup [60 mL] melted butter
2 tablespoons [30 mL] honey
2 teaspoons [10 mL] lemon juice
6 [4 to 6-ounce each] halibut steaks
Salt
Black pepper
Assortment of vegetables, for skewering</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Halibut with brie and toasted pecans</name>
        <category>Fish</category>
        <cuisine>Greek</cuisine>
        <directions>Dust halibut in flour. Shake off excess.

Heat butter in saute pan.

Add halibut and saute until golden brown or both sides.

Add whipping cream and brie pieces.

Bring to boil and reduce by one third by cooking until sauce thickens, approximately 2-3 min.

Add wine and serve topped with pecans.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 lb. fresh halibut fillets or chunks

1/2 cup flour
1 Tbl. clarified butter
3/4 whipping cream
1/4 lb. brie (cut into pieces)
1/8 cup white wine
1/4 cup toasted pecans
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Herb-Roasted Mediterranean Vegetables</name>
        <category>Vegetable</category>
        <cuisine>Other</cuisine>
        <directions>Toss veggie with oil garlic, rosemary and salt. Place in 15x10x1" baking pan.

Bake at 375 for 40 min. or until veggies are tender, stirring occasionally.

Sprinkle with cheese.</directions>
        <ingredients>8 c. assorted vegetables pieces (suchas eggplant, zucchini, onions, carrots and green peppers)
1/4 d. EVOO
2 cloves garlic, minced
2 tsp. dried rosemary leaves
1 tsp. salt
1/2 c. shredded parmesan cheese</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>6</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Herbed Tomato Soup with Pasta</name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Combine broth, diced russet potato, 1/4 c. green onion, chopped fresh parsley, chopped garlic, dried thyme and dried sage in large dutch oven. Simmer over medium heat until potato is tender about 15 min. Add spicy veggie juice and pasta; simmer until pasta is tender, stirring occasionally. about 8 min. Season to taste with salt and pepper.

Ladle soup into bowl. Garnish with remaining 1/4 cup green onion. Sprinkle cheese and croutons over if desired.</directions>
        <ingredients>5 C. canned chicken broth
1 large russet potato, peeled, diced
1/2 c. chopped green onions
1/4 c. chopped fresh parsley
4 large garlic cloves, chopped
1 tsp. dried thyme
1 tsp. dried sage
2 C. spicy veggie juice
1 C. small dried pasta (such as elbow macaroni) 2 fresh tomatoes
1 can tomato paste</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>12</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Homemade Soft Pretzels</name>
        <category>Soup</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Combine the water, sugar and kosher salt in the bowl of a stand mixer and sprinkle the yeast on top. Allow to sit for 5 minutes or until the mixture begins to foam. Add the flour and butter and, using the dough hook attachment, mix on low speed until well combined. Change to medium speed and knead until the dough is smooth and pulls away from the side of the bowl, approximately 4 to 5 minutes. Remove the dough from the bowl, clean the bowl and then oil it well with vegetable oil. Return the dough to the bowl, cover with plastic wrap and sit in a warm place for approximately 50 to 55 minutes or until the dough has doubled in size.

Preheat the oven to 450 degrees F. Line 2 half-sheet pans with parchment paper and lightly brush with the vegetable oil. Set aside.

Bring the 10 cups of water and the baking soda to a rolling boil in an 8-quart saucepan or roasting pan.

In the meantime, turn the dough out onto a slightly oiled work surface and divide into 8 equal pieces. Roll out each piece of dough into a 24-inch rope. Make a U-shape with the rope, holding the ends of the rope, cross them over each other and press onto the bottom of the U in order to form the shape of a pretzel. Place onto the parchment-lined half sheet pan.

Place the pretzels into the boiling water, 1 by 1, for 30 seconds. Remove them from the water using a large flat spatula. Return to the half sheet pan, brush the top of each pretzel with the beaten egg yolk and water mixture and sprinkle with the pretzel salt. Bake until dark golden brown in color, approximately 12 to 14 minutes. Transfer to a cooling rack for at least 5 minutes before serving.</directions>
        <ingredients>1 1/2 cups warm (110 to 115 degrees F) water
1 tablespoon sugar
2 teaspoons kosher salt
1 package active dry yeast
22 ounces all-purpose flour, approximately 4 1/2 cups
2 ounces unsalted butter, melted
Vegetable oil, for pan
10 cups water
2/3 cup baking soda
1 large egg yolk beaten with 1 tablespoon water
Pretzel salt</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>8</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Honey Bee Cookies</name>
        <category>Dessert</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Heat oven to 375.

Beat butter, brown sugar, honey and egg in a medium bowl on medium speed, scraping bowl constantly, until smooth. Stir in remaining ingredients.

Drop the dough by teaspoonfuls onto an ungreased cookie sheet.

Bake until set and light brown around edges (surfaces of cookies will appear shiny), 7 to 9 min. Immediately after removing from oven sprinkle with cinnamon-sugar. Let stand 3 to 5 min. before removing from cookie sheet. Place cookie on wire rack to cool.</directions>
        <ingredients>1/2 C. butter
1/2 C. packed brown sugar
1/2 C. honey
1 egg
1 1/2 C. flour
1/2 tsp. baking soda
1/2 tsp. salt
1/2 tsp. ground cinnamon</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
    <recipes>
        <name>Honey Sesame Chicken</name>
        <category>Poultry</category>
        <cuisine>American</cuisine>
        <directions>Mix flour and sesame seeds in medium bowl; set aside. Mix mustard and honey in small bowl. Brush chicken with mustard mixture; coat well with sesame seed mixture.

Heat oil in large skillet on medium heat. Add chicken; cook 4 to 5 minutes on each side or until coating is deep golden brown and chicken is no longer pink inside.

Prepare couscous as directed on paackage, adding zucchini and lemon juice afer stirring couscous into boiling liquid. Serve chicken with hot couscous mixture.</directions>
        <ingredients>1/4 c. all purpose flour
1/4 c. sesame seeds
2 Tbsp. Dijon mustard
1 Tbsp honey
4 boneless skinless chicken breast halves (about 1 1/4 lbs.)
2 Tbsp. Extra Virgin olive oil
1 pkg. Near East Herbed Chicken Couscous mix
2 medium zucchini, cut in quarters, lenghwise and sliced into 1/4 inch (about 2 cups)
</ingredients>
        <occasion>Other</occasion>
        <serves>4</serves>
    </recipes>
</Recipes>
